the video you're watching now is in 360
你现在正在观看的视频是360
resolution is not great but we wanted to
分辨率是不是很大，但我们想
try something different so if you're on
尝试不同的东西 ，如果你在
a desktop or laptop you can pan around
在台式机或笔记本电脑 ，你可以 左右 平移
with your mouse or if you're in a phone
用你的鼠标或 如果你在电话里
or tablet you should be able to just
或平板电脑，你应该能够 公正
move your device to look around
移动你的设备环顾四周
of course it's best viewed with a VR
当然，最好用VR观看
headset the video that follows is a
耳机后面的视频 是一个
guest lecture on machine learning that I
关于机器学习的客座讲座我
gave an MIT Sloan course on the business
麻省理工学院斯隆管理课程
of artificial intelligence the lecture
人工智能讲座
is non technical and intended to build
是非技术性的，打算建立
intuition about these ideas amongst the
关于 这些想法的 直觉
business students in the audience the
在观众中的商科学生
room was a half circle so we thought why
房间是半圈所以我们 想为什么
not film the lecture in 360 we recorded
没有拍摄我们录制的360的演讲
a screencast of the slides and pasted it
幻灯片的截屏视频并将其粘贴
into the video so that the slides are
到视频， 这样 的幻灯片
more crisp let me know what you think
更清脆让我知道你的想法
and remember it's an experiment so this
记得 这是一个实验， 所以 这个
course is talking about the broad
当然是在谈论广泛的
context the impact of artificial
上下文对人工的影响
intelligence the global there's global
全球的 情报 全球化
which is the global impact of artificial
这是人工的全球影响
intelligence says the business which is
情报说的是这样的业务
when you have to take these fun research
当你必须采取这些有趣的研究
ideas that I'll talk about today a lot
我来谈谈 今天的很多想法
of them are cool on toy examples when
他们 对玩具的例子 很酷
you bring them to reality you face real
你把它们带到现实， 你面对现实
challenges which is what I would like to
挑战是我 想要的
really highlight today that's the
今天真的很重要的是
business part when you want to make real
商业部分， 当你想要真正的
impact when you Miller make these
米勒做这些 时的影响
technologies of reality so I'll talk
现实技术所以我会谈
about how amazing the technology is for
关于 这项技术 的惊人之处
a nerd like me but also talk about how
像我这样的书呆子，也谈谈 如何
when you take that into the real world
当你把它带入现实世界
what are the challenges you face so
什么是 你面对 这样 的挑战
machine learning which is the technology
机器学习这是 技术
at the core of artificial intelligence
在 人工智能 的 核心
will talk about the promise the
将谈论承诺
excitement that I feel about it the
我 对此 感到兴奋
limitations will bring it down a little
限制会使它失去一点
bit what are the real capabilities the
什么是真正的能力
technology where for the first time
技术在哪里第一次
really as a civilization exploring the
真的是一个探索文明的文明
meaning of intelligence it is if you
如果你是智力的意义
pause for a second and just think you
暂停一秒钟 ，只是觉得你
know maybe of many of you want to make
知道也许你们许多人都想做
money out of this technology many of you
钱出来 这个技术很多的你的
want to save lives help people but also
想要拯救生命也 有助于 人们
in the philosophical level we get to
在我们得到的哲学层面
explore what
探索一下
makes us human so while I'll talk about
在我谈到的时候，让我们成为人类
the low-level technologies also think
低级 技术也在 思考
about the incredible opportunity here we
关于我们这里难以置信的机会
get to almost psychoanalyze ourselves by
得到几乎精神分析自己
trying to build versions of ourselves in
试图 建立自己的版本
the machine alright so here's the open
机器 还好，所以这里是 开放的
question how powerful is artificial
质疑人工是多么强大
intelligence how powerful is machine
智能 机器 有多 强大
learning that lies at the core of
学习是核心的
artificial intelligence is it simply a
人工智能 是一个简单的
helpful tool a special-purpose tool to
有用的工具专用工具
help you solve simple problems if your
帮助您解决简单问题， 如果你的
which is what it currently is currently
这就是它目前 是目前
machine learning artificial intelligence
机器学习人工智能
is a way if you can formally define the
是一种方式，如果你可以正式定义
problem you can formally define the
你可以正式定义的问题
tools you're working with you can
你正在与之合作的工具
formally define the utility function
正式定义效用函数
where you want to achieve with those
要实现这些
tools as long as you can define those
只要你可以定义那些工具
things we can come up with algorithms
我们 可以提出算法的东西
that can solve them as long as you have
只要 你有 ， 就能解决它们
the right kind of data which is all I'll
我所有的数据都是正确的
talk about data is key and the question
谈论数据是关键和问题
is into the future can we break past
进入未来我们能否突破过去
this very narrow definition of what
这个非常狭隘的定义 是什么
machine learning can give us which is
机器学习可以给我们哪个
solve specific problems to something
解决具体问题
bigger to where we approach the general
更接近我们接近将军的地方
intelligence that we exhibit as human
我们作为人类展示的 智慧
beings when we're born we know nothing
当我们出生时，众生一无所知
and we learn quickly from very little
我们很快就从中学到了很多
data the right answer is we don't know
数据正确答案是我们不知道的
we don't know what are the limitations
我们不知道有什么限制
of technology what kind of machine
技术 什么样的机器
learning are there there are several
学习有几个
flavors the first two is what's really
味道前两个是真的
the first is what's achieved success
首先是取得了哪些成功
today supervised learning what I'm
今天监督学习 我是 什么
showing here on the left of the slide is
显示在幻灯片左侧的是
the teachers is the data that is fed to
老师 是喂给 的数据
the system and on the right is the
系统 和右边是
students which is the system itself for
这是系统本身的学生
machine learning so they're supervised
机器学习所以他们受到监督
learning whenever everybody talks about
每个人 谈论 时都要学习
machine learning today what for the most
今天机器学习最多的东西
part they're referred to supervised
部分他们被提到 监督
learning which means every single piece
学习意味着每 一件作品
of data that is used to train the model
用于训练模型的数据
is seen by human eyes and those human
被人眼和那些人看见
eyes with an accompanying brain label
伴随着大脑标签的眼睛
that data
那些数据
in a way that makes it useful to the
以一种对它有用 的方式
machine this is this is critical because
机器 这是至关重要的，因为
that's one the blue box the human is
那就是 人类 的蓝盒子
really costly so whenever every single
真的很贵， 所以每当单身
piece of data that needs to be that's
数据块需要是的
used to train the machine needs to be
用来训练机器 需要
seen by a human you need to pay for that
一个人看到你需要为此付出代价
human and second you're limited to just
人类和第二，你只限于
the the time there's the amount of data
那个数据量的时间
necessary to label what it means to
必须标明它意味着什么
exist in this world is humongous
存在于这个 世界是巨大的
augmented supervised learning is when
增强的监督学习是什么时候
you get machine to really to help you a
你得到机器来真正帮助你
little bit there's a few tricks there
点点有一些小技巧 有
but still it's still only tricks it's
但它仍然只是欺骗它
still the human is at the core of it and
仍然是人类的核心和
the promise of future research that
未来研究的承诺
we're pursuing that I'm pursuing and
我们追求的是我追求和
perhaps in the applications if we get to
也许在应用程序中，如果我们到达
discuss or some of the speakers here get
讨论或一些 发言者在这里得到
to discuss they're pursuing in
讨论他们正在追求的
semi-supervised and reinforcement
半监督和强化
learning where the human starts to play
学习人类开始玩的地方
a smaller and smaller role in how much
一个越来越小的角色在多少
they get to annotate they have to
他们得到注释他们必须
annotate the data and the dream of the
注释数据和梦想
sort of Wizards of the dark arts of deep
一种深刻的黑暗艺术 奇才
learning are all excited about
学习都很兴奋
unsupervised learning that has very few
没有监督的学习 很少
actual successes in application in the
应用中的实际成功
real world today but it is the idea that
现实世界中，但今天 它的想法 ，
you can build a machine that doesn't
你可以建造一台没有的机器
require a human teacher a human being to
要求人类老师 是人
teach it anything is fills us artificial
教它什么都填补了我们的人为
intelligence researchers with excitement
情报研究人员兴奋不已
there's a theme here machine learning is
机器学习就是这里的主题
really simple the learning system in the
真的很简单 的学习系统
middle there's a training stage where
中间有一个训练阶段
you teach it something all you need is
你教它所需要的东西
some data input data and you need to
你需要一些数据输入数据
teach it the correct output for that
教它正确的 输出
input data so you have to have a lot of
输入数据，所以你必须有很多
pairs of input data and correct output
成对的输入数据和正确的输出
there'll be a theme of cats throughout
整个猫都会有一个主题
this presentation so if you want to
这种呈现方式，如果 你想
teach in a system difference being a cat
教导系统 差异是猫
and a dog you need a lot of images of
和一只狗， 你需要很多的图像
cats
猫
you need to tell it that this is a cat
你需要告诉 它 这是一只猫
this bounding box here and the images of
这个边界框和图像
cat you have to give it a lot of images
猫， 你必须给它很多图像
of dogs and tell it ok for this in this
狗，并告诉它 确定这个 在这个
in these pictures they're dogs and then
在这些照片中， 他们是狗，然后
then there's a spelling mistake on the
然后就是拼写错误了
second stage is the testing stage when
第二阶段是测试阶段
you actually give it new input it has
你居然给它新的输入有
never seen before and you hope that it
从未见过，你希望 它
has given for cat versus dog enough data
已经给了猫与狗足够的数据
to guess is this new image that I've
猜测这是我的新形象
never seen before a cat or a dog now the
猫或狗 以前 从未见过 的现在
one of the open questions do you want to
你想要的其中一个开放性问题
keep in mind is what in this world can
请记住这个 世界可以 做什么
we not model in this way what activity
我们不以这种方式模拟什么活动
what task what goal my I offer to you
什么任务我的目标是什么给 你
that there's nothing you can't model in
没有什么是你无法模仿的
this way so let's think about what in
这样，让我们​​考虑一下
terms of machine learning can be so it
机器学习方面可以如此 之
starts small what can be modeled in this
从小 开始 可以在这里建模
way first on the bottom of the slide
首先在幻灯片的底部
left is one-to-one mapping where the
左边是一对一的映射，其中
input is an image of a cat and the
输入是猫 和 猫的形象
output is a is a label that says cat or
输出是一个 标签，表示 猫或
dog you can also do one-to-many where
狗你也可以做一对多的地方
the image the input is a image of a cat
输入的图像 是猫 的图像
and the output is a story about that cat
而输出是 关于那只猫 的故事
captioning of the image you can first of
你可以先写下图像的字幕
all you can do the other way many to one
所有你可以做多对一的方式
mapping where you give it a story about
映射你给它讲故事的地方
a cat and it generates an image there's
一只猫，它会产生一个图像
many to many this is Google Translate we
很多人认为 这是 谷歌翻译我们
translate a sentence from one language
翻译一种语言的句子
to another
到另一个
and there's various flavors of that
并有那各种口味
again same theme here input data
这里同样的主题输入数据
provided with correct output and then
提供正确的输出然后
let it go into the wild where it runs on
让它进入 它运行的野外
input data hasn't seen before to provide
之前 没有提供输入数据提供
guesses and it's as simple as this
猜测， 就像 这一样简单
whatever you can come
无论你能来什么
into one of the following four things
成为以下四件事之一
numbers vector of numbers so bunch of
数字矢量的数字 所以束
numbers sequence of numbers or the
数字序列或数字
temporal dynamics matters so like audio
时间动态就像音频一样重要
video where the sequence the ordering
视频顺序排序
matters or sequence of vector numbers
事物或矢量数的序列
just a bunch of numbers if you can
如果可以的话，只是一堆数字
convert it into numbers and I propose to
把它转换成数字，我 建议
you that there's nothing you can't
你 有什么可以不
convert it to numbers if you can convert
如果你可以转换它转换为数字
it to numbers you can have a system
你可以拥有一个系统
learn to do it and the same thing with
学会做同样的 事情
the output generate numbers vectors and
输出生成数字向量和
numbers sequence the numbers or sequence
数字序列数字或序列
of vectors and numbers first
首先是矢量和数字
is there any questions at this point
这时有什么问题吗？
well we have a lot of fun slides to get
好吧，我们有很多有趣的幻灯片
through but I'll pause every once in a
通过，但我会暂停每一次
while to make sure we're on the same
同时要 确保 我们 一样
page here so what kind of input are we
这里的页面，我们是什么样的输入
talking about just to fly through it
谈论只是飞过它
images so faces or medical applications
图像面孔或医疗应用
for looking looking at scans of
看着扫描的
different parts of the body to determine
身体的不同部位来确定
if they're to diagnose any kind of
如果 他们要诊断任何一种
medical conditions text so conversations
医疗条件文本如此对话
your texts article blog posts for
你的文章文章博客文章
sentiment analysis question and
情绪分析问题和
answering so you ask it a question where
回答所以你问一个问题在哪里
the output you hope is answers sound so
你希望输出的答案听起来如此
voice recognition any kind of anything
任何形式 的语音识别
you could tell from audio time series
你可以从音频时间序列中看出来
data so financial data stock market can
数据如此金融数据股市可以
use it to predict anything you want
用它来预测任何你想要的东西
about the stock market including whether
关于股市是否包括
to buy or sell I think if you're curious
如果你好奇的话我买或卖
doesn't work quite well as a machine
作为一 台机器不能很好地工作
learning application physical world so
学习应用物理世界 所以
cars or any kind of object any kind of
汽车或任何类型的物体
robot that exists in this world so
存在于这个 世界上的机器人等等
location of where I am location of where
我在哪里的位置
other things are the actions of others
其他 事情是别人的行为
that could be all the input all of it
这可能是所有的输入
can be converted to numbers and the
可以转换为数字和
correct output same thing classification
正确输出相同的东西分类
a bunch of numbers classification is
一堆 数字分类是
saying is it's a cat or dog regression
说这是猫或狗的回归
is saying to what degree I turn the
是说我转向了什么程度
steering wheel sequence is generating
方向盘序列正在产生
audio generating video generating
音频生成视频生成
stories captioning
故事字幕
text images generate anything you could
文本图像可以生成任何内容
think of as numbers and at the core of
所认为的数量 和在核心
it is a bunch of data agnostic machine
它是一堆数据不可知的机器
learning algorithms there's traditional
学习算法是传统的
ones nearest neighbors Navy base support
最近邻国 海军基地支援
machine
机
support vector machines a lot of them
支持向量机 他们中 的很多
are limited in all describe how and then
在所有描述 如何然后限制
there's neural networks there's nothing
有神经网络什么都没有
special and new about neural networks
关于神经 网络的特殊和新的
and I'll describe exactly the very
我会精确描述 非常
subtle thing that is powerful that's
微妙的东西是强大的
always been there all along and certain
一直都在那里 ，确定
things have now been able to unlock that
事情现在已经能解开了
power about neural networks but it's
关于神经网络的力量， 但它是
still just the flavor of a machine
仍然 只是 一台机器 的味道
learning algorithm and the inspiration
学习算法 和灵感
for neural networks as Jonathan showed
对于Jonathan所展示的神经网络
last time is our human brain as perhaps
上一次 也许是我们的人类大脑
why the media perhaps why the hype is
为什么 媒体或许 为什么炒作
captivated by the idea of neural
被神经的想法迷住了
networks is because you immediately jump
网络是因为你 马上跳
to this feeling like because there's
这种感觉就像因为有
this mysterious structure to them that
这个神秘的结构对他们而言
scientists don't understand
科学家不明白
artificial neural networks I'm referring
人工神经网络我指的是
to and the biological ones we don't
以 和生物那些我们不
understand them and the similarity
了解他们和相似之处
captivates our minds that we think well
吸引我们的思想，我们认为好
this approach is perhaps as limited as
这种方法可能有限
our as limitless as our own human mind
我们作为自己的人类思想无限
but the comparison ends there in fact
但 事实上比较结束了
the artificial neuron their artificial
人工神经元 的人工
neural networks are much simpler
神经网络要简单得多
computational units at the core of
计算单位的核心
everything is this neuron if this is a
一切都是这个神经元，如果这是一个
computational unit that does a very two
这确实非常 两个计算单元
very simple operations on the left side
左侧非常简单的操作
it takes a set of numbers as inputs it
它需要一组数字作为输入
applies weights to those inputs sums
对这些投入金额应用权重
them together applies a little bias and
他们在一起施加了一点偏见
provides an output somewhere between 0
提供介于 0 之间的输出
and 1 so you can think of it as
和1所以你 可以把它想象成
computational entity that gets excited
兴奋的计算实体
when it sees certain inputs and gets
当 它看到某些输入并获得
totally turned off when it gets other
当它得到其他时完全关闭
kinds of inputs so maybe this neuron
各种输入也许这个神经元
with a zero with a point seven point six
零点七点六
one point four weights it gets really
真正得到一分四分之一的重量
excited when it sees pictures of cats
当它看到 猫的照片时很兴奋
and totally doesn't care about dogs some
并且完全不 关心狗的 一些
of us are like that so that's the job of
美国是这样 的 ，这样的的工作
this neuron it's to detect cats now what
这个神经元 现在可以检测猫是什么了
the way you build an artificial neural
你建立一个人工神经的方式
network the way you release the power
网络释放电源的方式
that I'll talk about in the following
我将 在下面讨论
slides about the applications what could
关于应用程序的幻灯片
be achieved
实现
it's just stacking a bunch of these
它只是堆叠了一堆这些
together think about it this is this is
一起想想这就是这个
a extremely simple computational unit
一个非常简单的计算单元
there so you need to sort of pause
所以你需要暂停一下
whenever we talk about the following
每当我们下面说说
slides and think that there there's a
滑动并认为那里有一个
few slides that I'll show that say
我将展示的几张幻灯片
neural networks are amazing now I want
现在 我想要 神经网络很棒
you to think back to this slide that
你回想起这张 幻灯片 是
everything is built on top of these
一切都建立在这些之上
really simple addition operations with
非常简单的加法操作
the a simple nonlinear function applied
应用了一个简单的非线性函数
at the end just a tiny math operation we
最后只是一个小小的数学运算我们
stack them together within a
内的 堆叠在一起他们
feed-forward way so there's a bunch of
前馈方式，以便有一堆
layers and when people talk about deep
层次和当人们谈论 深刻
neural networks it means there's a bunch
神经网络 意味着有一堆
of those layers and then there's
那些层然后就有了
recurrent neural networks that are also
复发神经网络也是
a special flavor that's able to have
一种特殊的味道，能够有
memory so as opposed to just pushing
记忆而不是仅仅推动
input into output directly it's also
直接输入到输出中也是如此
able to do stuff on the inside in a loop
能够做 的东西 在 里面在循环
where it remembers things this is useful
在那里它记住这是有用的东西
for natural language processing for
用于自然语言处理
audio processing whenever the sequence
每当序列进行音频处理
is not the length of the sequence is not
不是序列的长度 不是
defined okay slide number one in terms
定义好的幻灯片第一号
of neural networks are amazing
神经网络是惊人的
this is this is perhaps for the math
这可能是为了数学
nerds but also I want you to use your
书呆子，但我也希望你用你的
imagination there's a universality to
想象力有一种普遍性
neural networks means that this simple
神经网络意味着这很简单
computational unit on the left is an
左边的计算单位是
input on the right is the output of this
右边的输入是这个的 输出
network with just a single hidden layer
网络只有一个 隐藏层
it's called a hidden layer because it
它被称为隐藏层，因为它
sits there in the middle of the input
坐在输入的中间
and the output layers a single hidden
并且输出图层是单个隐藏的
layer with some number of notes can
有一些笔记的图层可以
represent any function any function that
代表任何功能的任何功能
means anything you want to build in this
意味着你想在这里构建任何东西
world everyone in this room can be
这个房间里的每个人都可以
represented with a neural network with a
用神经 网络表示
single hidden layer so the power and
单隐藏层所以权力和
this is just one hidden layer the power
这仅仅 是 一个隐层的电力
of these things is limitless the problem
这些事情 是无限的问题
of course is how do you find the network
当然是你如何找到网络
so how do you build a network that as as
那你怎么建立一个像那样的网络
clever as many of the people in this
聪明许多在此的人
room but the fact that you can build
房间，但 你可以建立 一个事实
such a network is incredible it's
这样的网络令人难以置信
amazing I want you to think about that
太棒了， 我想让你考虑一下
and the way you train a network so it's
以及你训练 网络的方式
born as a blank slate some random
一些随机出生的空白石板
weights assigned to the edges again a
再次分配给边缘的权重a
network is represented the numbers at
网络代表数字
the core the parameters of the core of
核心参数的核心
this network are the numbers on each of
这个网络是 每个 网络上的数字
those arrows each of those edges and you
那些边缘和 你的那些箭头
start knowing nothing this is a baby
开始不知道这是 一个婴儿
Network and the way you teach it
网络 和你教它的方式
something unfortunately currently as I
不幸的是，目前和我一样
said in a supervised learning mechanism
在监督学习机制中说
you have to give it pairs of input and
你必须给它一对输入和
output you have to give it pictures of
输出 你必须给它的 照片
cats and labels on those pictures saying
那些照片上的猫和标签 说
that they're cats and the basic
他们是猫和基本的
fundamental operation of learning is
学习的基本操作是
when
什么时候
you compute the measure of an error and
你计算一个错误的度量和
you back propagate it to the network
你回来传播它 到网络
what I mean
我的意思是说
everything is easier with cats I
猫咪一切都比较容易
apologize I apologize too many cats and
道歉我道歉太多的猫
so the input here is a cat and the
所以这里的输入是猫和
neural network we trained
神经网络我们训练
it's just guessing it doesn't know say I
它只是猜测它不知道说我
don't know it's guessing cat well it
不知道 它在猜 它好吧
happens to be right so we have to this
碰巧是正确的，所以我们必须这样做
is the measure of error yes you got a
是错误的衡量标准 是的，你有 一个
right and you have to back propagate
对，你 必须 回传播
that error you have to reward the
那个错误， 你必须奖励
network for doing a good job and all you
做好网络，做 你所有的 工作
do what I mean by a reward there's
做我的意思是奖励那里
weights on each of those edges and so
每个边缘上的权重等等
the the node that individual neurons
个别神经元的节点
that were responsible that back to that
这是负责任的
cat neuron that cat neuron needs to be
猫神经元需要的猫神经元
rewarded for seeing the cat so you just
因为 看到猫所以 奖励 你
increase the weights on the neurons that
增加神经元的权重
were associated with producing the
与生产有关
correct answer now you give it a picture
正确答案现在你给它一张照片
of a dog and the neural networks is cat
一只狗和 神经网络是猫
well that's an incorrect answer so no
这是一个错误的答案，所以没有
there's a high error needs to be back
有一个很高的错误需要 回来
propagated to the network so the weights
传播到网络 所以权重
are responsible with classifying this
负责对此进行分类
out of this picture as a cat need to be
这张照片就像猫一样需要
punished
处罚
they need to be decreased simple and you
他们需要简单地减少你
just repeat this process over and over
只是一遍又一 遍地 重复这个过程
this is what we do as kids when we're
这就是我们作为 孩子时 所做的 事情
first learning i I'm you know for the
第一次学习我 我，你知道的
most part that we have to
大多数情况下我们必须这样做
we're also supervised learning machines
我们也是有监督的学习机器
in the sense that we have our parents
从某种意义上说， 我们有我们的父母
and we have the environment the world
我们的环境 就是世界
that teaches about what's correct and
这教会了什么是正确的
what's incorrect and we back propagate
什么是不正确的，我们回来传播
this error and reward through our brain
这个错误和奖励通过我们的大脑
to learn the problem is as human beings
学习问题就像人类一样
we don't need too many examples and I'll
我们不需要太多的例子 ，我会
talk about some of the drawbacks of
谈谈一些 弊端
these approaches we don't need too many
这些方法我们不需要太多
examples you fall off your bike once or
你从自行车上掉下来的例子或者
twice and you learn how to ride the bike
两次，你学习如何骑自行车
unfortunately neural networks needs need
不幸的是神经网络需要
tens of thousands of times when they
当他们成千上万次
fall off the bike in order to learn how
脱下自行车，以了解如何
to not do it that's one of the
不要这样做是其中之一
limitation
局限性
and one key thing I didn't mention here
这里我没有提到一件关键的事情
is when we refer to input data it's when
就是当我们提到输入数据 的时候
we refer to input data we usually refer
我们指的是我们 通常 提到的输入数据
to sensory data raw data we have to
对我们必须的感觉数据原始数据
represent that data in some clever way
以某种聪明的方式表示数据
in some deeply clever way where we can
我们可以用一些非常聪明的方式
reason about it whether it's in our
理由是它 是否在我们的
brains or in the neural network in a
大脑或神经网络 中的
very simple example here to illustrate
这个非常简单的例子来说明
what representation of data matters so
什么样的数据表示如此重要
the way you represent the data can make
你表示 数据的方式可以做到
the discrimination of one class from
一个阶级的歧视
another a cat versus dog either
另一 只猫与狗
incredibly difficult or incredibly
难以置信的困难或难以置信
simple here is a visualization of the
这里简单的是可视化
same kind of data and Cartesian
同类数据和 笛卡儿
coordinates and polar coordinates on the
坐标和 极坐标
right you can just draw a simple line to
右边可以 只画一个简单的线
separate the two what you want is a
将你 想要 的两个分开是一个
system that's able to learn the polar
能够学习极地的系统
coordinate representation versus the
坐标表示与
Cartesian representation automatically
笛卡尔表示自动
and this is where deep learning has
这就是深度学习的地方
stepped in and revealed the incredible
介入并揭示了令人难以置信的
power of this approach which deep
这种 方法的力量深刻
learning is the smallest circle there is
学习是最小的圆 有
a type of representational learning
一种代表性学习
machine learning is the bigger second to
机器学习是 更大的第二次
the biggest up so this class is about
最大可达所以这个类 是有关
the biggest circle AI includes robotics
最大的圈子 AI 包括机器人
includes all the fun things that are
包括所有有趣的事情是
built on learning and I'll discuss while
建立在学习，我会讨论 ，而
machine learning I think will close this
机器学习我认为 会关闭这个
entire circle into one but for now AI is
整个圈子变为一个，但现在AI是
the biggest circle then a subset of that
最大的圆圈则 是 一个子集
is machine learning and a smaller subset
是机器学习和较小的 子集
of that is representation learning so
这就是代表性学习
deep learning is not only able to say
深度学习不仅 能说
given a few examples of cats and dogs to
给猫狗的几个例子
discriminate between a cat and a dog
区分猫与狗
it's able to represent what it means to
它能够代表 它意味着什么
be a cat it's so it's able to
做一只猫， 它就能做到
automatically determine what are the
自动确定是什么
fundamental units
基本单位
at the low level and the high level
处于低水平和高水平
talking about this very Plato what it
谈论 这个非常柏拉图 是什么
means to represent a cat from the
指表示从猫
whiskers to the high level shape of the
胡须到高水平的形状
head to the the fuzziness and the
前往模糊和
deformable aspects of the cat not a cat
猫的变形方面不是猫
expert but I hear this these are the
专家，但我听说这些是
features of a cat verses that are
猫的经文特征
essential to discriminate between a cat
区分猫的必要条件
and a dog learning those features as
和狗一样学习这些特征
opposed to having to have experts this
反对必须有专家
is the drawback of systems that Jonathan
是乔纳森系统的缺点
talked about from the 80s and 90s where
谈到了80年代和90年代的地方
you have to bring in experts for any
你必须为任何人带来专家
specific domain that you try to solve
您尝试解决的特定域
you had to have them encode that
你必须让他们编码
information deep learning this is this
信息深入学习 就是这个
is simply the only big difference
只是唯一的大不同
between deep learning and other methods
在深度学习和其他方法之间
is that it learns the representation for
是，它 为 学习的代表性
you it learns what it means to be a cat
你了解成为一只猫意味着什么
nobody has to step in and help it figure
没有人必须介入并帮助它
out what what that cats have whiskers
那些猫有什么胡须
and dogs don't what does this mean the
和狗不是什么意思
fact that it can learn these features
事实上， 它可以学习 这些功能
these whisker features is as opposed to
这些胡须特征与之相反
having five or ten or a hundred or five
有五个或十个或一百个或五个
hundred features that are encoded by
由...编码的数百个功能
brilliant engineers with PhDs it can
有博士学位的优秀工程师可以
find hundreds of thousands millions of
找到数十万的
features automatically hundreds of
功能自动数百个
millions of features so stuff that that
数以百万计的特征 ，使得东西，那
can't be put into words are described in
不能投入 中描述的话
fact it's one of the limitations the
事实上它是其中一个局限性
neural networks is they find so many
神经网络是他们发现的 那么多
fundamental things about what it means
关于它意味着什么的基本要素
to be a cat that you can't visualize
成为一只 你无法想象 的猫
what it really knows it just seems to
它 真正知道它似乎只是
know stuff and it finds that stuff
知道的东西 ，它发现了那些东西
automatically what what does this mean
自动是什么意思
it's the critical thing here is because
这是至关重要 的 ，因为
it's able to automatically learn those
它能够 自动学习这些
hundreds of millions of features it's
数以亿计的 功能
able to utilize data it doesn't start
能够利用它无法 启动的 数据
the diminishing returns don't hit on
收益递减不会发生
until what we don't know when they hit
直到我们不知道他们什么时候打
the point is with the classical machine
关键在于经典机器
learning algorithms you start hitting a
学习算法你开始 打
wall when you have tens of thousands of
当你有成千上万的墙
images of cats with deep learning you
深刻了解你 的猫的图像
get better
好转
better with more data neural networks
更好的数据神经网络
are amazing slide two here's here's a
是惊人的幻灯片两个在这里是一个
game a simple arcade game where there's
游戏是一个简单的街机游戏
two paddles the bouncing a ball back and
两个桨弹跳球回
forth okay great
来回 好大
you can figure out an artificial
你可以计算出人工
intelligence agent that can play this
可以发挥此作用的情报人员
game it can and not even that well just
游戏它可以和甚至没有干脆
kind of it kind of learns to do all
有点学会做所有
right and eventually win here's the
对，并 最终赢得 这里的
fascinating thing with deep learning as
深刻学习的迷人之处
opposed to encoding the position of the
反对编码的位置
paddles the position of the ball having
划桨球 的位置
an expert in this game as many come in
很多人都参与了这个游戏的专家
and encode the physics of this game the
并编码这个游戏的物理特性
input to the neural network is the raw
输入到神经网络是原始的
pixels of the game so it's learning in
游戏的像素，它的学习
the following way you give it an
你给它一个以下方式
evolution of the game you give it a
你给它一个 游戏的进化
bunch of pixels pixels are you know
你知道一堆像素像素
images are built up of pixels they're
图像是由像素构成的
just numbers from 0 to 256 so there's
只是从0 到256的数字所以有
this array of numbers that represent
这个数字代表的数组
each image and then you give it several
每个图像，然后你给它几个
tens of thousands of images they're
他们成千上万的图像
represented game so you have the stack
代表游戏，所以你有堆栈
of pixels and stack of images that
像素和 图像 的堆叠的那
represents a game and the only thing you
代表 一个游戏，你唯一的事情
know this giant stack of numbers the
知道这个巨大的 数字 堆栈
only thing he knows at the end you won
他唯一知道的就是你赢了
or lost that's it so based on that you
或者丢失它就是基于你
have to figure out how to play the game
必须弄清楚 如何玩游戏
you know nothing about games you know
你对自己认识的游戏一无所知
nothing about colors or balls or paddles
没有颜色或球或桨
or winning or anything that's it so this
或获胜或其他任何事情
is it's why is this amazing that it even
这就是为什么 这甚至 是 惊人的
works and it works too it wins it's
工作，它也有效，它赢得了 它
amazing because that's exactly what we
令人惊讶，因为这正是我们的意思
do as human beings this is general
像人一样这是一般的
intelligence so I need you to pause and
智力， 所以我需要你暂停和
think about this well we'll talk about
想想这个，我们会谈谈
special intelligence - the usefulness
特殊情报 - 有用
and it ok there's cool tricks here and
并 确定有这里的很酷的技巧和
there that we can do to get you an edge
在那里我们可以做到让你有优势
on your high-frequency trading system
在你的高频 交易系统上
but this is general intelligence general
但这是一般情报 一般
intelligence is the same intelligence we
智力是 我们的智慧
use as babies when we're born what we
为婴儿使用，当我们出生的 我们
get is an input sensory input of image
get是图像的输入感官输入
sensory input right now all of us most
感觉输入正确的 我们现在所有的最
of us are seeing hearing feeling with
我们正在看到听到的感觉
touch and that's the only input we get
触摸，这是我们得到的唯一输入
we know nothing and with that input we
我们什么都不知道，我们对此有所了解
have to learn something
必须学习 一些东西
nobody is pre teaching us stuff and this
没有人是前教我们的东西，这
is an example of that a trivial example
是一个简单 例子的例子
but one of the first examples where this
但这是第一个 例子 之一
is truly working I sorry to linger on
我真的很努力， 我很抱歉苟延残喘
this but it's a fundamental fact the
这是一个基本的 事实
fact that we have systems that and now
事实上，我们 现在 拥有系统
outperform human beings in these simple
在这些简单的表现中胜过人类
arcade games is incredible
街机游戏令人难以置信
this is the research side of things but
这是事物的研究方面
let me step back these again the
让我再次退一步了
takeaways that previous slide is why I
以前的幻灯片是我的原因
think machine learning is limitless in
认为机器学习是无限的
the future currently it's limited again
目前的未来再次受到限制
the representation of the data matters
数据的表示很重要
and if you want to have impact we
如果你想要有影响 我们
currently can only tackle the small
目前只能解决小问题
problems what are those problems image
问题是什么问题形象
recognition we can classify given the
认可我们可以分类给予
entire image of a leopard of a boat of a
一条船的豹的整个图像
mite with pretty good accuracy of what's
螨具有非常好的准确性
in that image
在那个图像
that's image classification what else we
这是图像 分类我们还有什么
can find exactly where in that image
可以找到该图像的确切位置
each individual object is that's called
每个单独的对象都被称为
image segmentation again the same the
图像分割再次相同
process is the same as the learning
过程 与学习 相同
system in the middle and neural network
系统在中间 和神经 网络
as long as you give it a set of numbers
只要你给它 一组数字
as input and the correct set of labels
作为输入和正确的标签集
as output it learns to do that for data
作为输出， 它学会了为数据做到这一点
hasn't seen the best let me pause a
没见过最好让我暂停一下
second and maybe if you have any
第二，也许你有任何
questions does anyone have any questions
问题是否有人有任何 问题
about
关于
the techniques of neural networks yes
神经网络的技术是的
so that's a great question and in a
所以这是一个很大的问题 ，并在
couple of slides I'll get to it exactly
几张幻灯片，我会完全理解它
so the the the data representation I'll
所以数据表示 我会
elaborate in a little bit but loosely
稍微复杂但松散地阐述
the data representation is for a neural
数据表示用于神经
network is in the weights of each of
网络是 每个的权重
those arrows that connecting your ons
那些 连接 你的 插件 箭头
that's where the representation is so
这就是代表所在的地方
I'll show to really clarify that example
我将展示真正澄清这个例子
of what that means the Cartesian versus
什么 意思笛卡尔 与
polar coordinates is just the visual
极坐标就是视觉
very simple visualization of the concept
非常简单的概念可视化
but you want to be able to represent the
但你希望能够代表
data in an arbitrary way where there's
数据以任意方式存在
no limits to the representation it could
它的表现没有限制
be highly nonlinear highly complex any
高度非线性高度复杂的任何
other questions
其他问题
so I have a couple of slides almost
所以我几乎有几张幻灯片
asking this questions because there's no
问这个 问题，因为没有
good answers but one could argue and I
好的答案，但 有人可以争辩，我
think somebody in last class brought up
认为上一堂课的人长大了
that you know is machine learning just
你知道的只是机器学习
pattern recognition it's possible that
模式识别它有可能
reasoning thinking is just pattern
推理思维只是模式
recognition and I'll describe sort of an
承认 ， 我会描述一下
intuition behind that so we tend to
背后的直觉所以我们倾向于
respect thinking a lot because we've
尊重思考，因为我们已经
recently as human beings learned to do
最近正如人类学会做的那样
it in our evolutionary time we think
它在我们思考的进化时期
that it's somehow special from for
从某种程度上来说它是特别的
example perception we've had visual
例如， 我们有视觉 感知
perception for several orders of
感知几个订单
magnitude longer in our evolution
我们进化的时间更长
evolution as a living species we've
进化作为我们 生活的物种
started to learn to reason I think about
开始学习的原因，我想
a hundred thousand years ago so we think
十万年前 我们这么想
it's somehow special from the same kind
它在某种程度上 与同类 特殊
of mechanism we use for seeing things
我们用来看东西的机制
perhaps it's exactly the same thing it's
或许这与 它 完全相同
so perception is pattern recognition
因此感知是模式识别
perhaps reasoning is just a few more
也许理由是短短更多
layers of that that's the hope that's an
那这就是希望这是 一个层
open question it's
打开问题吧
yes that's a great question there
是的，那是一个很好的问题
there's been very few breakthroughs in
在这方面几乎没有什么突破
your networks since through the AI
你的网络通过人工智能
winters that we discussed through a lot
我们经常讨论的冬天
of excitement in spurts and even
兴奋 ，甚至是兴奋
recently there's been a very few
最近有一些人
algorithmic innovations the big gains
算法创新获得巨大收益
came from compute so improvements in GPU
来自计算所以GPU的改进
and better faster computers the you
而且你的计算机速度更快
can't underestimate the power of
不能低估的力量
community so the ability to share code
社区所以能够共享代码
and the internet ability to communicate
和 互联网沟通的能力
together through the internet and work
通过互联网 和工作一起
on code together and then digitization
代码一起然后数字化
of data
数据的
so like ability to have large datasets
所以 想 有大型 数据集 的能力
easily accessible and downloadable all
易于 访问和下载所有
of those little things but I think it in
这些小事情，但我 认为
terms of the future of deep learning and
深度学习和 未来 的条款
machine learning it it all rides on
机器学习它一切都骑
compute I think meaning continued bigger
计算我认为意义继续更大
and faster computers that doesn't
更快的计算机 没有
necessarily mean Moore's law in making
一定意味着摩尔定律在 制作
small and smaller chips it means getting
小而小的芯片 意味着得到
clever in different directions massive
在不同的方向聪明大量
parallelization coming up with ways to
并行化提出了方法
do super efficient power efficient
做超高效的电源效率
implementations and neural networks and
实现和神经 网络和
so on so let me just fly through a few
等等，让 我飞过几个
examples of what we can do with machine
我们可以 用机器做 什么的例子
learning just to give you a flavor I
学习只是为了给你一种味道
think in future lectures as possible
在未来的讲座中尽可能地思考
we'll discuss different speakers the
我们将讨论不同的音箱
different specific applications really
真的不同的具体应用
dig into those so we can as opposed to
挖掘那些我们可以相反的东西
working with just images you can work
使用你可以工作的图像
with videos and segments those I
视频和细分 我
mentioned image segmentation we do video
提到图像分割我们做视频
segmentation so through video segments
通过视频 片段进行细分
the different parts of a scene that's
那个场景的不同部分
useful to a particular
对特定有用
application here and driving you can
在这里申请并驾驶你可以
segment the road from cars and
从汽车和汽车分割道路
vegetation and lane markings you can
你可以 植被和车道标记
also a subtle but important point these
这些 也是 一个微妙 但重要的 观点
very small piece of information that we
很小 的 资料 片 ，我们
just we know are important like there is
只是我们知道是很重要的 像有
a red light like I have to stop I have
像我必须停下来的红灯一样
to slow down so hard questions so the
慢慢这么难的 问题所以
question was how do you detect the
问题是你是如何发现的
traffic light and lights so how do we do
交通灯和灯这样我们怎么做
it as human beings first of all let's
它作为人类首先让我们
start there the way we do it is by the
从这里开始，我们 做 的方式 是由
knowledge we'll bring to the table so we
我们将带来的知识 ， 所以我们
we know what it means to be on the road
我们知道在路上 意味着什么
there's a lot of the huge network of
这里有很多 庞大的网络
knowledge that you come with and so that
你带来的 知识 等等
makes the perception problem much easier
使感知问题更容易
this is pure perception you take an
这 是你采取的纯粹感知
image and you separate different parts
图像和你分开不同的 部分
based purely on tiny patterns of pixels
完全基于微小的像素图案
so first it finds all the edges and it
所以首先它找到所有 的边缘和它
learns that traffic lights have certain
得知交通 灯 确定
kinds of edges around them and then zoom
它们周围的各种边缘然后缩放
out a little bit they have a certain
他们有一点肯定
collection of edges that make up this
构成这个 的边缘的集合
black rectangle type shape so it's all
黑色矩形类型的形状，所以这一切
about shapes it kind of build up knowing
关于形状它有点建立知识
this this shape structure of things but
这种形状结构的东西但是
it's a purely perception problem and one
这是一个纯粹的感知问题和一个问题
of the things that argue is that if it's
争论的事情是， 如果是的话
purely a perception approach and you
纯粹是一种感知方法和你
bring no knowledge to the table about
把没有的知识表 约
the physics of the world the
世界的 物理学
three-dimensional physics and the
三维物理学和
temporal dynamics that you are now going
时间动态的， 你现在要
to be able to successfully achieve near
要能够成功 实现近
100% accuracy and some of the
100％的准确性和一些
so that's exactly the right question is
所以这是正确的 问题
you for all of these things think about
你所有这些 事情想想
how you as a human being would solve
你作为一个人将如何解决
these problems and what is lacking in
这些问题和缺乏的问题
the machine learning approach what data
机器学习方法有哪些数据
is lacking in the machine learning
缺乏机器学习
approach in order to achieve the same
方法是为了达到同样的目的
kind of results the same kind of
那种结果是同一种
reasoning required to that you would use
您 需要使用的 推理
as a human so there is also image
作为一个人，所以也有形象
detection image detection which means
检测图像检测意味着
the subtle but important point the stuff
这些东西微妙而重要
I've mentioned before image
我之前提到的图像
classification is given them image of a
分类给他们一个图像
cat you find the cat noting the side you
猫， 你发现猫注意到你的一面
don't find the cat you say this images
找不到你说这张图片的猫
of a cat or not and then detection or
一只猫 与否，然后检测或
localization is when you actually find
本地化就是你真正找到的时候
where in the image that is that problem
图像 中的哪个位置就是那个问题
is much harder but also doable with
更难， 但也可以
machine learning with with deep neural
机器学习与深度神经网络
networks now as I said inputs outputs
网络现在正如我所说的输入输出
can be anything the input could be a
可以是 任何 输入可能是 一个
video the output could be video and you
视频输出可能是视频和你
could do anything you want with these
可以做任何你想要的东西
videos you can colorize the video you
您可以为视频着色的视频
can add take an old black-and-white film
可以添加一个旧 的黑白 电影
and produce color images again in terms
然后 再次 生成彩色图像
of being out in terms of having an
在拥有一个
impact in the world using these
使用这些 对 世界的 影响
applications you have to think this is a
您必须认为这 是一个 应用程序
cool demonstration but how well does it
很酷的演示， 但 它 有多好
actually work in the real world
实际上在 现实世界中工作
translation whether that's from text to
翻译是否是从文本 到
text or image to image you can translate
文本或图像到图像，您可以翻译
here dark-chocolate from one language to
这里的黑巧克力 从一种语言到
another it's class global business of
另一个它的全球业务
artificial intelligence there's a
人工智能 有一个
reference below there you can go and
你可以去下面参考
generate your own text you can generate
生成您 可以生成的 自己的 文本
the writing of the act of generating
写作的产生
handwriting so you can type in some text
手写， 所以你可以输入一些文字
and given different styles that it
并赋予 它 不同的风格
learns from other handwriting samples it
从其他手写样本中学习它
can generate any kind of text using
可以使用生成任何类型 的文本
handwriting
手写
again the input is language the output
再次输入是语言输出
is a sequence of writing of pen
是笔的一系列写作
movements on the screen you can complete
你可以完成屏幕上的动作
sentences this is kind of a fun one
句子这是 种乐趣之一
where if you start
如果你开始的话
so you can generate language you can
这样你就可以生成语言 ，您 可以
generate language where you start you
生成你开始的语言
feed the system some input first so in
首先向系统输入一些输入
black there's says life is and then have
黑色有说生命 然后有
the neural network complete those
神经网络完成那些
sentences life is about kids life about
句子寿命大约为孩子们 的生活 有关
life is about the weather there's a lot
生活 是 关于天气 有很多
of knowledge here
这里的知识
I think being conveyed and you can start
我认为正在传达，你可以开始
the sentence with the meaning of life is
生命含义的句子是
the meaning of life is literary
生命的意义是文学的
recognition true for us academics or the
对我们学者或学者的认可是真实的
meaning of life is the tradition of
生命的意义是传统
ancient human production also true but
古代人类 生产也是 如此
these are all generated by a computer
这些都是由计算机生成的
you can also caption this has been
你也可以说明这一点
become very popular recently is caption
最近变得非常受欢迎的是标题
generation given us input as an image
一代人给我们输入 图像
the output is a set of text the cap
输出是一组 文本的上限
captures the content of the image you
捕获您的图像内容
find the different objects in the in the
找到中的不同对象
image that's a perception problem and
像这是一个疑虑的问题 ，
once you find the different objects you
一旦你找到了不同的物体
stitch them together in a sentence that
在一个句子它们拼接说
makes sense
说得通
you generate a bunch of sentences and
您生成一串句子 和
classify which sentence is the most
分类哪个句子最多
likely to fit this this image and you
可能适合这个图像和你
can so certainly in the I tried to avoid
在我试图避免的时候可以这么肯定
mentioning to driving too much because
提到驾驶太多因为
it is my field with this what I'm
这就是我的领域
excited about what then the moment I
兴奋 那么 一刻我 什么
start talking about driving it'll all be
开始谈论 驾驶 一切都会
about driving so but I should mention of
关于 驾驶 ，但我应该提到
course the deep learning is critical to
当然，深度学习至关重要
driving applications for the both the
推动两者的 应用
perception and what is really exciting
感知和真正令人兴奋的事情
to us now is the end-to-end the
对我们来说 现在是 端到端 的
end-to-end approach so whenever you say
无论何时你说，端到端的方法
end-to-end in any application what that
在任何应用程序中 端到端 是什么
means is you start from the very raw
意思是你从非常原始的开始
inputs that the system gets and you
系统得到的输入和你
produce the very final output that's
产生十分最终输出这
expected of the system so supposed to in
预计该系统 ， 使 应该在
the self-driving car case as opposed to
相对于自驾车的情况下
breaking a car down into each individual
把车撞到每个人身上
components of perception localization
感知定位的组成部分
mapping control planning and just taking
绘图控制计划和刚刚采取
the whole stack and just ignoring all
整个 堆栈，只是忽略所有
the super complex problems in the middle
中间的超级复杂问题
just taking the external scene as input
只需将外部场景作为输入
and as output produced steering and
并且作为输出产生转向和
acceleration of braking commands
制动命令 的加速度
and so in this way taking this input is
所以这样输入就是这样的
the image of the external world in this
在这个 外部 世界的形象
case in a Tesla we can generate steering
在特斯拉的情况下我们可以产生转向
commands for the car again input a bunch
汽车的命令再次输入一堆
of numbers that that's just images I'll
数字， 这 只是我 的 图像
put a single number that gives you the
把单号， 给你的
steering of the of the car okay
汽车的转向没问题
so let's step back for a second and
所以让我们退后一步一秒钟 ，
think about what can't we do with
想想 我们 能用 不
machine learning we talked we talked
机器学习我们谈过 我们谈过
about you can map numbers to numbers
关于你可以将数字映射 到数字
let's think about what we can't do this
让我们考虑一下我们做不到的事情
at the core of artificial intelligence
在人工智能的核心
in terms of making an impact on this
在对此产生影响方面
world is robotics so what can't we solve
世界 是机器人，所以我们无法解决
in robotics and artificial intelligence
在机器人 和人工智能
with a machine learning approach and
用机器学习方法和
let's break down what artificial
让我们分解一下人为的
intelligence means here's a stack
智力意味着这里是一个堆栈
starting at the very top is the
从最顶端开始是
environment the world you operate in
环境你操作 的世界
their sensors that sense that world
他们的感应器感知那个世界
there is feature extraction and learning
有特征提取和学习
from that data and there's some
从那些 数据 ，有一些
reasoning planning and effectors are the
推理计划和效应器是
ways you manipulate the world what can't
你操纵 世界的方式不可能
we learn in this way so we've had a lot
我们以这种方式学习，所以我们有很多
of success as Jonathan talked about in
乔纳森谈到 的 成功
the history of AI with formal tasks
人工智能与正式任务的历史
playing games solving puzzles recently
最近 玩游戏解决难题
we're having a lot of breakthroughs with
我们有很多的突破 与
medical diagnosis we're still we're
医学诊断我们仍然是
still struggling but are very excited
仍在苦苦挣扎， 但非常兴奋
about in the robotic space with more
在更多的机器人空间
mundane tasks of walking of basic
基本的步行世俗任务
perception of natural language written
对自然语言的感知
and spoken and then there is the human
说话然后就是人
tasks which are perhaps completely out
任务可能完全没有
of reach of this pipeline at the moment
目前该管道的覆盖范围
is cognition imagination suggests a
是认知想象力暗示一个
subjective experience so high-level
主观经验如此 高层次
reasoning not just common sense or high
推理不只是常识或高
level human level reasoning so let's fly
水平的人类 推理所以让我们飞翔
through this pipeline they're sensors
通过这条管道，他们是传感器
cameras lidar audio
相机激光雷达音响
there is communication that flies to the
有是拥有到 所述 通信
air or wired or wireless or wired I am
空气或 有线或无线或有线我
you measuring the movement of things so
你衡量事物的运动，使
that's the way you think about it that's
那你想想的方式 ，是
the way assuming beings and as any kind
假设存在和任何种类的方式
of system that you design you measure
您设计您测量 系统
the world you don't just get an API to
世界上你不只是获得API
the world you need to somehow measure
你需要以某种方式衡量的世界
aspects of this world so that's how you
这世界的方方面面就是你的方式
get the data so that's how you convert
得到数据，这就是你如何 转换
the world into data you can play with
将世界转化为可以玩的数据
and once you have the data this is the
一旦你掌握了数据，这就是了
representation side you have to convert
表示方面你必须转换
that raw data of raw pixels of raw audio
原始音频的原始像素的 该原始 数据
raw lidar data you have to convert that
原始 激光雷达数据 你必须转换它
into data that's useful for the
进入对数据有用的数据
intelligence system for the learning
学习智能系统
system to to use to discriminate between
系统用于区分
one thing and another for vision that's
这是另一回事
finding edges corners object parts and
找到边角对象部分和
entire objects
整个物体
there's the machine learning that I'll
有机器 学习我会
talk about that I've talked about
谈谈我已经谈过的事情
there's different kinds of mapping of
有不同种类的映射
the representation that you've learned
你学到的表现形式
to an actual outputs there is once you
实际产出有一次你
have this so you have this idea of and
有这个所以你有这个 想法和
this goes to maybe a little bit of
这可能是一 点点
Simon's question is reasoning this is
西蒙的问题是推理这是
something that's out of reach or machine
一些遥不可及的东西或机器
learning at the moment this is going to
现在正在学习
your question then we can we can build a
你的问题，我们可以建立一个
world-class machine learning system for
世界一流的 机器学习系统
taking an image and classifying that
拍摄 图像并对其进行分类
it's a duck I wonder if this will work
它是一只鸭子， 我想知道 这是否会奏效
wake you up so we could take this is
叫醒你， 所以我们可以接受这个
well studied exceptionally well studied
研究得非常好
problem could take audio sample of a doc
问题可以采取 文档的 音频样本
and tell that it's a duck
并告诉它 它是一只鸭子
in fact what species of bird it's
事实上它是什么种类的 鸟
incredible how much research there is in
令人难以置信的多少研究存在
bird species classification and you can
鸟类分类，你可以
look at video and we could tell that we
看看视频，我们可以告诉我们
can do extra recognition that it's just
可以做到额外的认可，这是公正的
swimming but we can't do with learning
游泳，但我们不能学习
now is reason that if it looks like a
现在是理由，如果它看起来像一个
duck it swims like a duck and quacks
它像 鸭子 和嘎嘎 一样游泳
like a duck is very likely to be a duck
如鱼得水 很可能是 鸭子
this is the reasoning problem this is
这是推理问题
the task that I personally am obsessed
我个人 很痴迷的任务
with and that I hope that machine
和我希望那台机器
learning can close and then there is the
学习可以关闭，然后有
planning action and the effectors
规划行动和效应器
so this is another place where machine
所以这是机器的另一个地方
learning has not had many strides
学习并没有取得多大进展
there's mechanical issues here that
这里有机械问题
incredibly difficult the degrees of
令人难以置信的困难度
freedom with all the actuators involved
涉及所有执行器的 自由
with all the just just the ability to
只有能力才能
localize every party yourself in this
在 这里 本地化 每一方
dynamic space where things are
事物的动态空间
constantly changing when there's degrees
有学位的时候不断变化
of uncertainty when there's noise just
不确定性的时候，那里已经 只是 噪音
that basic problem is exceptionally
这个基本问题非同寻常
difficult
难
let me just pose this question we talked
让我谈谈我们谈到的这个问题
about how machine what machine learning
关于机器如何机器学习
can do with the cats and the duck we
我们可以做猫和鸭
could do that given a representation it
鉴于 它 的 代表，它可以做到这一点
could predict what's in the image but
可以预测图像中的内容但是
one of the open questions is and deep
其中一个悬而未决的问题 是深刻的
learning has been able to do the feature
学习一直能够做到的功能
extraction the representation learning
提取表示学习
this is the big breakthrough that
这是一个重大的突破
everybody's excited about but can also
每个人都很兴奋，但也可以
reason these are the open questions in a
这些是 开放式问题的原因
reason can it do the planning in action
是因为它能够在行动中进行规划
and as human beings do can it close the
而作为人类， 它可以关闭
loop entirely from sensors to effectors
从传感器到效应器完全循环
so learn not only the brain but the way
所以 不仅要 学习 大脑，还要 学习
you sense the world and the way you
你感受世界和你的方式
affect the world
影响世界
it the so the question was about the
所以问题是关于
pong game thank you talk to it a little
乒乓球比赛谢谢你说一点
longer it it doesn't get punished when
更长的时间 它不会受到惩罚
it doesn't detect the ball this is the
它不检测的球 ， 这是
beautiful thing it gets punished only at
美丽的东西 它只有 在 处罚
the very end of the game for losing the
比赛 的最后 输了
game and gets her water for winning the
游戏并赢得她的水
game so it knows nothing about that ball
游戏所以它对 那个球 一无所知
and it learns about that ball that's
并且它了解那个球
something you really sit and think about
你真正坐下来思考的东西
has like how do as human beings imagine
喜欢人类如何 想象
if you're playing with a physical ball
如果你正在玩一个实体球
how do you learn what a ball is you you
你怎么知道你是谁？
get hurt by it you like squeeze and you
受到伤害你喜欢挤压你
throw it you feel the dynamics of it the
扔了吧，你觉得 它的 动态
physics of it and nobody tells you about
它的物理学和没有人告诉你
what a ball is you're just using the raw
什么 球你只是使用 原料
sensor input we take you for granted
传感器输入我们 理所当然
and maybe this is what I can end on is
也许这就是我能结束的
this is what's something Jonathan
这就是 乔纳森
brought up is we take the simplicity of
长大是我们采取简单 的
this task for granted because we've been
这项任务理所当然，因为我们一直都是
we've had eyes we broadly speaking as
我们广泛地说过我们的眼睛
living species on planet Earth there's
地球 上的生物物种
eyes have been evolved for 540 million
眼睛已经进化了5.4亿
years so we have 540 million years of
所以我们有5.4亿年的时间
data we've been walking for close to
我们一直走近的数据
that bipedal mammals we have been
我们生活过的双足哺乳动物
thinking only very recently so a hundred
最近才思考 这么一百个
thousand years versus a hundred million
千年与一亿
years and that's why we can't some of
年，这就是为什么我们不能一些
these problems that we're trying to
我们正在努力 解决 这些 问题
solve you can't take for granted how
解决你不能理所当然的如何
actually difficult they are so for
实际上很难 他们这样做
example this is the marvex paradox the
例如，这就是marvex悖论了
Jonathan brought up is that the easy
乔纳森 长大就是 那么容易
problems are hard the things would think
事情会想到的问题很难
are easy actually really hard this is
实际上很容易这很难
state-of-the-art robot on the right
最先进的机器人在右边
playing soccer and that was a
踢足球，那是一个
state-of-the-art human on the left
左边 是最先进的人类
playing soccer
踢足球
and I'll give it a second the question
我会给它一个问题
was you know there's a fundamental
你知道 有根本吗？
difference between the way with train
与火车 的方式之间的 差异
your networks and the way we've trained
你的网络和我们训练的方式
biological neural networks for evolution
用于进化的生物神经网络
by discarding through natural selection
通过自然 选择 丢弃
a bunch of the the the the neural
一堆神经
networks that didn't work so well
网络效果不佳
that's so first of all the process of
首先是这个 过程
evolution is I think not well understood
进化是我认为不太了解
meaning sorry the raw huh says he
意思是对不起 生 吧，他说：
careful here the role of evolution in
小心这里 进化的作用
the evolution of our cognition of our
我们对自己的认识的演变
intelligence I don't know if that's so
情报我不知道是不是这样
this is an open question
这是一个悬而未决的问题
so maybe clarify this point his neural
所以也许澄清这一点 他的神经
networks artificial neural networks are
网络人工神经网络是
fixed for the most part in size this is
大部分是 固定的， 这 是
exactly right it's like a single human
完全正确它就像一个人
being that gets to learn we don't have
正在学习我们没有
mechanisms of of modifying or revolving
修改或旋转的机制
those neural networks yet although you
那些神经网络，尽管 你
could think of researchers as doing
可以想象研究人员在做什么
exactly that
确切地说
there you have grad students working on
你有研究生在那里工作
different neural networks and the ones
不同的神经网络和那些
that don't do a good job don't get
那个做得不好 不要搞定
promoted and get a good you know there
在那里升职并获得一份好消息
is a natural selection there but other
是其他的自然选择
than that it's a it's an open question
而这是一个悬而未决的问题
stay tuned and keep your head up because
请继续关注并 保持 头脑 ，因为
the future I believe is really promising
我相信 未来 真的 很有希望
and the slides will be made available
并将提供幻灯片
for sure
当然
I think a lot of the explorations of
我想了很多的探索中
what it means to build an intelligent
建立智能化意味着什么
machine has been in sci-fi movies we're
机器一直 在 我们 的科幻 电影
now beginning to actually make it a
现在开始真正做到了
reality this is Space Odyssey to keep
现实这 是Space Odyssey要保留的
with that theme in the previous lecture
在上一讲的主题中
go ahead this is as opposed to the
继续这 是与之相反的
dreamlike monolith view when the
梦幻般的巨石景观时
astronaut is gazing out into the open
宇航员正凝视着空地
sky at the stars we're going to look at
我们要看的星星的天空
the practice of AI today and how we go
今天人工智能的实践以及我们如何前进
if you're familiar with the movie when
如果你对这部电影很熟悉的话
this new technology appeared before our
这项新技术出现在我们面前
eyes in we're full of excitement how we
我们的眼中充满了兴奋
transfer that into actual practical
转移到 实际的实际
impact on our lives to quickly review
对我们生活的影响要快速审查
what we talked about last time we I
我们谈到了 我们 最后一次 我
presented the technology and asked the
提出了技术并问了
question of whether this technology
这是否技术问题
merely serves a special purpose to
只是为了一个特殊的目的
answer specific tasks that can be
回答可以做的具体任务
formalized or whether it can be through
正式化或是否 可以通过
through the process of transferring the
通过转移的过程
knowledge learned on one domain be
知识 在一个域得知 是
generalizable to where an intelligent
推广到 其中一个 智能
system that's trained in a small domain
在小范围内训练的系统
can be used to achieve general
可以用来实现一般
intelligent tasks like we do as human
像我们一样做人类的智能任务
beings the this is kind of a stack of
众生这是种一叠
artificial intelligence of going from
从去人工智能
all the way up into the top of the
一路成的顶部
environment the world
环境世界
the sensors sets the data the the
传感器设置数据
intelligence system the way it perceives
智能 系统 一旦 发觉 的 方式
this world then once you have this you
这个世界， 一旦你有了这个你
convert the world into some numbers you
将世界转换为某些数字
able to extract some representation of
能够提取一些表示
that world and this is where machine
那世界和这 就是机器
learning starts to come into play and
学习开始发挥作用
then there's the part where I rate I
再有就是我打分 我的一部分
will raise it again today is can machine
今天 会再提高它 是可以机器
learning be doing the following steps to
学习做以下步骤
that we can do very well as human beings
我们 可以做的非常 好作为人类
is the reasoning step you know you can
是你知道的可以 推理的步骤
tell the difference in a cat and a dog
告诉猫与狗的区别
but can you now start to reason about
但你现在可以开始推理
what it means to be alive what it means
活着意味着什么意味着什么
to be a cat with living creature and
成为一个有 生物和生物的猫
what it means to be this kind of
这是什么意思 是这样的
physical object or this kind of physical
物理对象或这种物理对象
object and take what's called common
反对并采取所谓的共同点
sense things we take for granted start
我们认为 理所当然的 事情 开始
to construct models of the world through
通过构建世界的模型
reasoning Descartes I think therefore I
推理笛卡尔因此我想
am
上午
we want our neural networks to
我们想要我们的神经网络
come up with that on their own and once
拿出与 自己的 ，一旦
you do that action you'll go right back
你做那个动作你会马上 回来
into the world you start acting in that
进入世界，你开始行动
world so the question is can machine
世界所以问题是 可以机器
learning can this be learned from data
学习可以从数据中学习
or does do experts need to encode the
还是专家需要编码
knowledge of reasoning the knowledge of
推理知识的知识
actions the set of actions that's kind
采取行动的一系列 行动
of the question open questions I raise
问题 悬而未决的 问题我 养
it continues throughout the talk today
它在今天的谈话中继续
and so as we start to think about how
所以我们开始思考如何
artificial intelligence especially
特别是人工智能
machine learning as it realizes itself
机器学习，因为它实现了自己
through robotics gets to impact the
通过机器人技术 来影响
world we start thinking about what are
世界， 我们开始思考什么是
the easy problems what are the hard
简单的问题是什么是 硬
problems and it seems to us that vision
问题在 我们 看来是 这个愿景
and movement walking is easy because
和行走步行很容易，因为
we've been doing it for millions of
我们已经做 了数以百万计 的
years hundreds of millions of years and
数亿 年 和数 年
thinking it's hard reasoning is hard I
认为这很难推理我很难
propose to you that it's perhaps because
向你提出这可能是因为
we've only been doing it for a short
我们只做了一小段时间
time and so so think we're quite special
时间 等所以认为 我们很特别
because we're able to think so we have
因为我们能够 这么想
to kind of question of what it's easy
以 什么 样 的，很容易 问题
and what is hard because when we start
什么是困难，因为当我们开始
to develop some of these systems and
开发其中一些 系统 和
what you start to realize that all these
你开始怎么 知道 这些
problems are equally hard so the problem
问题同样困难所以问题
of walking that we take for granted the
走路， 我们理所当然 的
actuation and the physical the ability
驱动和物理 能力
to recognize where you are in the
识别你在哪里
physical space the sense the world
物理空间感觉 世界
around you to deal deal with the
在你周围处理
uncertainty of the perception problem
感知问题的不确定性
and then so all of these robots by the
然后所有这些机器人由
way this is for the most recent DARPA
这是最近的DARPA的方式
challenge which MIT was also part of and
挑战这MIT也是 的 一部分 ，
so what what are these robots doing they
那么这些 机器人在做什么呢
they don't have any they only have
他们没有他们唯一的
sparse communication with human beings
与人类稀疏通信
on the periphery so most of the stuff
在外围 所以大部分的东西
they have to do autonomously like get
他们必须 像get 一样自主地做
inside a car this is an MIT robot
在车内，这是一个麻省理工学院的机器人
unfortunately that they have to get in
不幸的是， 他们必须进入
the car and the hardest tasks they have
汽车和他们最艰难的任务
to get out of the car that's walking so
走出那辆走路的车
this kind of raises to you the very real
这种对你 非常真实 的提升
aspect here you want to build
这方面你要建立
applications that actually work in the
实际工作的应用程序
real world and that's the first
现实世界，这是 第一次
challenge an opportunity here
在这里挑战机会
than many of the technologies we talked
比 我们谈过的 许多技术
about currently crumble under the the
关于目前的 下崩溃
reality of our world when we transfer
我们这个世界 的 现实 ，当我们转移
them from a small data set in the lab to
他们从 实验室 的小数据集 到
the real world for the computer vision
计算机视觉 的现实世界
is perhaps one of the best illustrations
也许是最好的 插图之一
of this computer vision is the task as
这个计算机视觉的任务是
we talked about of interpreting images
我们谈到了解释图像
and so when you there's been a lot of
所以，当你有 很多
great accomplishments on interpreting
口译方面的巨大成就
images cats versus dogs now when you try
当你尝试时，现在 想象猫与狗
to create a system like the Tesla
创建像特斯拉这样的系统
vehicle that I've often that we work
我经常工作的车辆
with and I always talk about is it's a
和我一直在谈论的是它是一个
vision based robot right as radar for
基于视觉的机器人就像雷达一样
basic obstacle avoidance but most of the
避免基本的障碍，但大多数
understanding of the world comes from a
对世界 的了解来自于
single monocular camera now they've
单眼单反相机现在他们已经
expanded the number of cameras but for
扩大了相机的数量，但是
the most time there's been a hundred
大部分时间还有的已经 有 一百
thousand vehicles driving on the roads
千辆车在路上行驶
today with a single essentially a single
今天只有一个单一的
webcam so when you start to do that you
摄像头，所以当你开始这样做的时候
have to perform all of these extraction
必须执行所有这些提取
of texture color optical flow so the the
纹理颜色光流如此
movement through time temporal dynamics
通过时间 动态的运动
of the images you have to construct
您必须构建的图像
these patterns construct the
这些模式构成了
understanding of objects and entities
理解对象和实体
and how they interact and from that you
以及他们如何与你互动
have to act in this world and that's all
必须在这个 世界 上行动，这 就是全部
based on this computer vision system so
基于这种计算机视觉系统
it's no longer cats versus dogs it's
它不再是猫与狗 是
it's a huge detection of pedestrians or
这是对行人或行人的巨大发现
the wrong classification the wrong
错误的分类错了
detection is the difference between life
检测是生命的区别
and death so let's look at cats those
和死亡所以让我们看看 那些 猫
were things a little more comfortable so
是 的东西 多一点舒适 ，所以
computer vision and I would like to
计算机视觉和我想
illustrate to you why this is such a
向你说明为什么会这样
hard task which we've talked about we've
我们已经谈到 ，我们已经硬任务
been doing it for 500 million years so
这样做了5亿 年
we think it's easy computer vision is
我们认为 计算机视觉很 容易
actually incredible so all you're
实际上令人难以置信，所以你都是
getting with your human eyes is you're
你的人眼是这样的
getting essentially pixels in there's
在那里获得基本上像素
light coming into your eyes and all
光线进入你的眼睛和所有
you're getting is the reflection from
你得到 的是从反射
the different surfaces in here of light
光 在这里的不同表面
and there's perception they're sensors
并且他们认为他们是传感器
inside your eyes can
你的眼睛里面可以
burning that into numbers it's really
把 它烧成数字 真的
very similar to this numbers in this in
与此中的数字非常相似
the case of what we use with computers
我们用于计算机的情况
RGB images or the individual pixels that
RGB图像或单个 像素
are numbers from 0 to 255 so 256
是 从 0到255的 数字 ， 所以 256
possible numbers and there's just a
可能的数字，只有一个
bunch of them and that's all we get we
一堆他们 ，这就是我们得到的一切
get a collection of numbers where
得到一组数字在哪里
they're spatially connected ones that
他们是空间连接的
are close together are part of the same
紧密相连是 同 一部分
object so cat-cat pixels are all
对象所以cat-cat像素都是
connected together that's the only thing
连接在一起这是唯一的事情
we have to help us but the rest of it is
我们必须帮助我们， 但 剩下的就是
just numbers intensity in hours and we
只是 数小时 强度 和我们
have to use those numbers to classify
必须使用这些数字进行分类
what's in the image and if you really
什么是图像，如果你真的
think about it this is a really
想想 看 ，这是一个真正的
difficult task all you get is these
你得到的艰巨任务就是这些
numbers how the heck are you supposed to
数字你 应该 怎么样
form a model of the world with which you
形成与你相关的世界模型
can detect pedestrians with a with
可以检测与行人用
really 99.99999% accuracy because these
真的是99.99999％的准确度，因为这些
pedestrians are these cars are cyclists
行人是这些车是骑自行车的人
in the car context or any kind of
在汽车的背景下或任何一种
applications you're looking at even if
即使您正在查看的应用程序
your job is in the factory floor to
你的工作是在工厂车间
detect the the defective gummy bears
检测有缺陷的小熊
they're flying past that like a hundred
他们飞过了那 一百个
miles an hour
一小时一英里
your task is you don't want that bad
你的任务是你不要那么糟糕
gummy bear to get by that your product
粘性熊来得到你的产品
and the the brand will be damaged
而且该品牌将 受到损害
however serious are not serious your
无论如何严重并不严重
application is what you have to be you
应用程序就是你必须成为的人
have to have a computer vision system
必须 有一个计算机视觉系统
that deals with all of these aspects
与 所有的这些方面涉及
viewpoint variation scale variation no
视点变异尺度变化no
matter the size of the object is still
无论是规模的目标 仍 是
the same object then no matter the
无论如何 ，同一个对象
viewpoint from which area you look at
从哪个区域看你的观点
that object is still the same object the
那个对象仍然是同一个对象
lighting that moves with lighting
随着照明而移动的照明
consistent here because we're indoors
这里一致，因为我们在室内
but when you're outdoors or you're
但是当你在户外或你的时候
moving the scene is moving the lighting
移动场景正在移动照明
the complexity of the lighting
照明的复杂性
variations is incredible from the
变化令人难以置信
illumination to just the movement of the
照亮只是运动的
different objects in the scene I think
我认为 场景中有不同的物体
about you and this particular one it's
关于你和这个特殊的一个 很
Twilight and the light is changing I
暮色和 光正在改变我
think you know almost every time I Drive
我想你几乎每次开车都知道
there's one or two
有一两个
things that I see there really that I'm
我看到的东西真的 是 我
drawing like 200 million years in order
按顺序绘制2 亿年
to be able to figure out it's not it's a
能够弄清楚它不是一个
guy who's open his car door and I can't
那个打开车门的家伙我不能
see him but I can just see the light
看到他但我能看到光明
doesn't look quite right on that side of
不看的那一侧完全正确
the road and I'm yeah somehow I know I
道路，我是，我知道我
might in my mind it's a person but it
可能在我看来它是一个人，但它
seems like a almost impossible problem
似乎是一个几乎不可能的问题
for the machines to get right I will
为了让机器正确，我会
argue that that the pure perception task
认为那是纯粹的感知任务
is too hard that you come to the table
来到 桌子上 太难 了
as human beings with all this huge
作为拥有这一切的巨大人类
amount of knowledge that you're not
你不 知道的知识量
actually interpreting all the complex
实际上解释所有的复杂
lighting variations that you're seeing
您正在看到的灯光变化
you actually know enough about the world
你对这个世界了解得足够多
enough about your commute home enough
足够 你的通勤回家
about the way the kinds of things you
关于 你的事情 的种类
would see in this world about Boston
会在这个世界上看到波士顿
about the way pedestrians move there's a
关于行人移动的方式是一个
certain light of day you bring all that
你带来所有这一切的一天
to the table that makes the perception
到了 产生感知 的桌子
task doable and that's one of the big
任务可行，这是一个大的
missing pieces in the technology as I'll
我会 缺少技术中的碎片
talk about that's the open problem of
谈到 这 的公开问题
machine learning it's how to bring all
机器学习它是如何带来所有
that knowledge
那知识
first of all build that knowledge and
首先建立知识和
then bring that knowledge to the table
然后将这些知识带到桌面上
as opposed to starting from scratch
而不是 从头开始
every time and so Katz the promise gets
每次卡西都有这样的 承诺
okay so the to me occlusion for most of
好吧所以对我来说大多数的闭塞
the computer vision community this is
这 是计算机视觉社区
one of the biggest challenges and it
最大 的 挑战 之一 ，
really highlights how far we are from
真的突出了我们的距离
being able to reason about this world
能够推理 这个 世界
occlusions are when what what an
闭塞 是什么时候什么的
inclusion is is when the objects you're
包含就是你的对象
trying to detect something about
试图发现一些事情
classify the object detect object the
对象检测对象进行分类
object is blocked partially by another
对象被另一个部分阻止
object in front of them this is
在他们面前的对象是这样的
something you think it's trivial perhaps
你认为这也许是微不足道的
you don't even really think about it
你甚至没有真正考虑 过它
because we we reason a three-dimensional
因为我们推理一个三维的
way but the occlusion aspect is is makes
的方式，但阻塞方面是是品牌
makes perception incredibly difficult so
使得感知极其困难等等
we have to design is think about this so
我们要设计就是这么想的
this image is converted into numbers and
此图像转换为数字和
we for the task of detecting is there a
我们的检测任务是有一个
cat in this image yes or no you have to
在这张图片中的猫是或否你必须
be able to reason about this image with
能用这个 图像来推理
object in the scene most of us are able
在我们大多数人 能够的场景中的对象
to very easily detect if there's a cat
很容易发现是否有猫
in this image we're able to detect that
在这张图片中 我们能够检测出来
there is a cat in this image now think
现在 想想 这个 图像中 有一只猫
about this there's a single eye and
关于这一点，只有一只 眼睛和
there's an ear so you have to think
有一个耳朵所以你必须思考
about what is it part of our brain that
什么是 我们的大脑 的一部分
allows us to understand to suppose that
让我们理解这一点
with some high degree of accuracy that
具有一定的高度准确性
there's a cat here in this picture I
这里有一只猫在 这张照片 我
mean the degree of occlusion here is
意味着这里的咬合 程度
immense
巨大
and so I promise so this is for most of
所以我 保证 这是大多数的
you some of you will think this is in
你们当中有些人 会 认为这是在
fact a monkey eating a banana but I
事实上一只猴子吃香蕉 但是我
would venture to say that most of us are
我敢说 我们 大多数 人都是
able to tell it's nevertheless a cat you
能够告诉它你是一只猫
watch this for hours and so let me give
看这几个小时，让我给
you another this is kind of a paper
你是另一个这 是一篇论文
that's often cited our set of papers to
这经常引用我们的论文集
illustrate how difficult computer vision
说明计算机视觉有多难
is how thin the line that we're walking
我们走的路线有多薄
with all of these impressive results
所有这些令人印象深刻的结果
that we've been able to show recently in
我们最近能够展示的
the machine learning community in this
这个机器学习社区
case for deep neural networks are easily
深度神经网络的情况很容易
fooled paper the seminal paper at this
在这篇文章中愚弄了这篇 开创性的论文
point shows that when you apply network
点显示 当 您应用 网络时
trained on imagenet so basically on
在图像网上训练， 所以基本上
detecting cats versus dogs or different
检测猫与狗或不同
categories in inside images if you're
如果你是内部图像中的类别
you can find an arbitrary number of
你可以找到任意数量的
images that look like noise up in the
看起来像 在 噪声 高达 图像
top row where the algorithm used to
算法习惯的顶行
classify those images in the image net
在图像网中对这些图像进行分类
of cat versus dog is able to confidently
猫与狗的关系能够 自信
say with 99.6% accuracy or above that
说具有 99.6％的 准确度或高于此值
it's seeing a robin or a cheetah or an
它看到了知更鸟或猎豹或者
armadillo or a panda you know in that
犰狳或你知道 的熊猫
noise
噪声
so it's confidently saying given this
所以它自信地说这个
noise that that's obviously a robin so
噪音，这显然是知更鸟所以
you have to realize that the kind of
你必须意识到那种
this is patterns the kind of processes
这是模式的过程
it's using to understand what's
它用于了解什么是
containing the
含有
image is purely a collection of patterns
图像纯粹是模式的集合
that it has been able to extract from
它已经能够 从中 提取出来
other images that has been human
其他 人类的 图像
annotated by humans and that perhaps is
人类注释那或许是
very limiting to trying to create a
非常有限的尝试创建一个
system that's able to operate in the
系统能够在
real world this is a very sort of this
现实世界这是 一种非常类型 的东西
is very clean illustration of that
很干净举例说
concept and the same you can confidently
你可以自信地概念和相同
predict and those images below where
预测和那些图像在哪里
there are strong patterns it's not even
有强烈的模式甚至不是
noise strong patterns that have nothing
噪音强烈的模式，什么都没有
to do with the entities being detected
做 与被 检测 的实体
again confidently that same algorithm is
再次自信地 认为相同的算法是
able to see a penguin a starfish a
能看到企鹅 海星
baseball in the guitar in the in that
棒球在吉他中
noise a more serious for people
噪音对人们来说 更 严重
designing robots like myself in the on
设计像 我这样的 机器人
the sensor side you can flip that and
传感器一侧你可以翻转它
say I can take a image and I can distort
说我可以拍一张照片而且我可以扭曲
it with some very little amount of noise
它有一些非常少的噪音
and if that if that noise is applied to
如果那个噪音适用于
the image I can completely change the
图像我可以 完全 改变
confident prediction about what's in
关于 内容的自信预测
that image so to explain what's being
那个图像 是为了 解释现在的情况
shown so on the left and the column on
在左侧和列上显示如此
the left and again here what's the the
这里左边和右边是什么的
same kind of neural network is able to
同一种神经网络能够
predict accurately confidently that
准确地预测自信 地
there is a dog in that image but if we
那张照片中有一只狗 但是如果我们的话
apply just a little bit of noise to that
适用于噪声到 的 只是一点点
image to produce that image
生成 该图像的图像
imperceptible to our human eyes the
察觉不到我们人类的眼睛
difference between those two the same
两者 之间的 差异 相同
algorithm is is saying that there is
算法是说 ，有
confidently in an ostrich in that image
自信地在那张照片中的鸵鸟
so another thing to really think about
所以要 真正 考虑 另一件事
that noise can have such a significant
噪音可以有这么大的意义
impact on the prediction of these
对这些预测的影响
algorithms this is really really quite
算法这真的非常
honestly out of all the things I'll say
诚实地说， 我会说的所有事情
today and I'm aware of one of the
今天，我知道其中一个
biggest challenges of machine learning
机器学习的最大挑战
being applied in the real world is
在现实世界中应用是
robustness how much noise can you add
坚固性你可以添加多少噪音
into the system before everything falls
在一切都崩溃之前进入系统
apart so how do you validate sensors so
除此之外你如何验证 传感器
say a car company has to produce a
说汽车公司必须生产一个
vehicle and it has
车辆，它有
sensors in that vehicle how do you know
在车辆 传感器 你怎么知道
that that those sensors will not start
这些传感器无法启动
generating slight noise due to
产生由于轻微噪音
interference of various kinds and
各种干扰
because of that noise instead of seeing
因为那种噪音 而不是看到
a pedestrian you will see nothing or the
一个行人， 你什么也看不见
opposite you'll see pedestrians
对面你会看到行人
everywhere so of course the most
当然最无处不在
dangerous is when it will not see an
危险的是什么时候看不到
object and collide with it in the case
在这种情况下反对并与之碰撞
of cars
汽车
there's also spoofing which a lot of
还有很多欺骗行为
people as always with security people
人们一如既往的安全人士
are really concerned about and perhaps
真的很关心也许
people here are really concerned about
这里的人真的很在意
this issue I think this is a really
这个问题我 认为这是真的
important issue but because you can
重要的问题，但因为 你可以
apply noise and convince the system that
应用噪音并说服系统
you're seeing an ostrich when there is
你有鸵鸟的时候会看到它
in fact no ostrich you can do the same
事实上， 没有鸵鸟你可以做同样的事情
thing in a in an attacking way so you
以攻击方式进行的事情让你如此
can attack the sensors of a car and make
可以攻击汽车的传感器并制造
it believe like with lidar spoofing so
它相信像激光雷达欺骗一样
spoof lidar radar or ultrasonic sensors
恶搞激光雷达或超声波传感器
to believe that you're seeing
相信你在看
pedestrians when they're not there and
当他们不存在行人和
the opposite to hide pedestrians make
隐藏行人的相反方向
pedestrians invisible to the sensor when
行人无形到传感器时
they're in fact there so whenever you
无论何时你都在这里
have Indulgence systems operating in
让Indulgence系统运行
this world they become susceptible to
这个世界他们变得易受影响
the fact that everything so much of the
事实上，一切都那么大的
work is done in software and based on
工作是在软件中 完成 的 并且基于
sensors so at any point in the chain if
传感器，所以在链中的任何一点如果
there's a failure you have to be able to
你必须 能够做到失败
detect that failure and right now we
检测到失败，现在我们
have no mechanisms for automatically
没有自动机制
detecting that failure so on the data
检测 到 数据 失败 等
side so one challenge is that we're
那么一个挑战 就是我们
constantly dealing with is that we are
经常处理 的是我们
the algorithms in machine learning
机器学习中的算法
algorithms that we're using our need
我们正在使用 我们需要的 算法
labeled data and we have very little
标记数据 ，我们很少
labeled data labeled data again is when
标记数据 再次 标记为数据
you have pairs of input data and the
你有成对的输入数据和
ground truth the the true label
真相是真正的标签
annotation class that that image belongs
该图像 所属的注记类
to or concept and the it doesn't have to
或概念， 它不必
be an image it could be any source of
是一个图像，它可以是任何来源
data it's a really costly process to do
数据是一个非常昂贵的过程
so because it's so costly we
因为它太贵了我们
rely every breakthrough we've had so far
依靠我们迄今为止所取得的每一项突破
relies on that label data and because of
依赖于标签数据 和因
its cost we don't have much of it so all
它的成本，我们没有太多的 它，因此所有
the problems that come from data can
来自数据的问题 可以
either be solved by having a lot more of
要么通过拥有更多的东西来解决
this data which I believe is most people
这个数据我认为是大多数人
believe it's too challenging it's too
相信它也太具有挑战性了
challenging to have human beings
有人类的挑战
annotate huge amounts of data or we have
注释大量数据或我们有
to develop algorithms that are able to
开发能够的算法
do something with the unlabeled data its
做一些未标记的 数据
the unsupervised semi-supervised
无监督的半监督
sparsely supervised reinforcement
疏忽监督加固
learning as we talked about last time I
学习， 因为 我们上次谈到 我
mention again here so one way you
这里再一次 提到 你
understand something about data when you
当你了解数据时
don't have labels is you reason about it
没有标签是你的理由
all you're given is a few facts when
你给出的都是一些事实 时
you're a baby your parents give you a
你是一个孩子， 你的父母给 你一个
few facts and you go into this world
很少有事实，你进入这个世界
with those facts and you grow your
有了这些事实 ，你就会成长
knowledge graph your knowledge base your
知识图表你的知识库你的
understanding of the world from those
从那些人那里了解世界
few facts we don't have a good method of
我们没有一个很好的方法
doing that an automated unrestricted way
这样做是一种自动化的 无限制方式
the inefficiency of our learners the
学习者 的低效率
machine learning algorithms I've talked
机器学习算法 我已经谈过了
about the neural networks need a lot of
关于神经网络 需要很多
examples of every single concept that
每个概念的例子
they're given in order to learn anything
他们是为了学习任何东西而给出的
about them thousands tens of thousands
他们成千上万
of cats are needed to understand what
猫需要了解什么
the spatial patterns at every level the
每个层面的 空间格局
representation of a cat the visual
一只猫的视觉表现
representation would cap we don't we
代表会限制 我们不是我们
can't do anything with a single example
用一个例子做不了什么
there's a few approaches but nothing
有一些方法，但没有
quite robust yet and we haven't come up
非常强大，我们还没有上来
with a way this is also possible to make
用这种方式 也可以 做到
annotation this labeling process somehow
以某种方式注释这个标签过程
be very cheap so leveraging this is
非常便宜， 所以利用 这个
something being called human computation
被称为人类计算的东西
that term has fallen out of favor a
那个词 已经失宠了
little bit one of my big passions is
我最大的激情之一就是
human computation is using something
人类计算正在使用某种东西
about our behavior something about what
我们的行为是关于什么的
we do in this world online or in the
我们在这个 世界上在线 或 在线
real world to annotate data
现实 世界注释数据
automatically so for example as you
自动，例如你
drive which is what we do everybody has
驱动这是我们每个人都有的
to draw
画画
and we can collect data about you
我们可以收集有关您的 数据
driving in order to train self-driving
开车以便 训练 自驾车
vehicles to to to drive and that's a
要开车的车辆，那是一个
free annotation so here are the
免费注释所以这里是
annotated data sets we have the
我们有注释的数据集
supervised learning data sets
监督学习数据 集
there's many but these are ones some of
有很多，但这些都是那些 部分
the more famous ones from the very from
从一较为有名的 从
the toy data sets of M NIST
M NIST的玩具数据集
- the large broad arbitrary categories
- 广泛的任意类别
of images data sets and there which is
图像 数据集和那里
what image net is and there's in
什么形象网是什么和那里
healthcare there's an audio there's an
医疗保健有一个声音有 一个
video there's are you know there's a
视频， 你知道有一个
huge number of data sets now but each
现在大量的数据集，但每个
one of them is usually in the scale of
其中一个通常是在规模
hundreds of thousands millions tens of
数十万甚至数十万
millions not billions or trillions which
百万不是数十亿或数万亿哪些
is what we need to create systems that
就是我们需要建立系统， 其
operate in the in the real world and
在现实 世界中 运作
again these are the kinds of machine
再次这些是机器的种类
learning algorithms we have there's five
学习算法我们有五个
listed here the teachers on the left is
这里列出的是左边的老师
what is what is the input to the system
什么是系统 的输入
that requires to Train it from the
这需要从中 训练
supervised learning at the very top is
最顶层的监督学习是
what we have all of our successes and
我们所有的成功和成就
everything else is where the promise
其他一切都是承诺的地方
lies the semi-supervised the
是半监督的
reinforcement or the fully unsupervised
加固或完全 无监督
learning where the input from the human
学习 从人类 那里输入
is very minimal and another way to think
是非常小的另一种 思考方式
about this so every whenever you think
关于这一点，每当你想到的时候
about machine learning today
关于机器学习 今天
whenever somebody talks about machine
每当有人 谈论机器时
learning what they're talking about is
学习他们正在谈论的 是 什么
systems that memorize that memorize
记住记忆的系统
patterns and so this is one of the big
模式，所以这是一个大的
criticisms of the current machine
批评当前的机器
learning approaches where all they're
他们所有的学习方法
doing is you're providing there only as
这样做是你只 为提供有
good as the human annotated data that
良好的人类注释数据
they're provided we don't have
它们是我们没有提供的
mechanisms for actually understanding
实际理解的 机制
you can pause and think about this in
你可以暂停，并 在 思考这个
order to create an intelligent system it
为了创造一个智能 系统吧
shouldn't just memorize it should
不应该只记住它应该
understand the representations inside
理解里面的表达
that data in order to operate in that
那些数据是为了 在那里运作
world and that's the open question one
世界，这是一个悬而未决的问题
of them and one of the challenges and
其中一个 挑战和挑战
opportunities for machine learning
机器学习的机会
researchers today is to extend machine
今天的研究人员正在扩展机器
learning
学习
memorization to understanding this is
记住要理解这一点
that duck the reasoning if you get
如果你得到的话就是这样的理由
information from the perception systems
来自 感知系统的信息
that it looks like a duck from the audio
它看起来像是音频中的鸭子
processing that it quacks like a duck
处理 它像鸭子一样嘎嘎叫
and then from video classification that
然后从视频分类
it the activity recognition that it
它的活动 认识 到它
swims like a duck
像鸭子一样游泳
the reasoning step is how to connect
推理步骤是如何连接
those facts to then say that it is in
那些事实然后说它是在
fact a duck okay so that's on the
事实上，鸭子 还好，所以就是这样
algorithm side and the data side now
算法端和数据端现在
this is one of the reasons compute
这是计算的原因之一
computational power computational
计算能力计算
hardware that is at the core of the
硬件是核心的
success of machine learning so our
机器学习的成功就这样
algorithms have been the same since the
自从以来算法一直都是一样的
60s since the 80s 90s depending on how
自80年代90年代以来的60年代取决于如何
you're counting the big breakthroughs
你在计算重大突破
came and compute so there's Moore's law
来到和计算所以有摩尔定律
most of you know the way our the CPU
大多数人都 知道我们的CPU方式
side of our computers works for a single
我们的计算机的一面适用于单一的
CPU is that it's for the most part
CPU 就是它的大部分内容
executing a single action at a time in a
在a中一次 执行一个动作
sequence so sequential very different
顺序如此顺序非常不同
from our brain which is a massively
来自我们的大脑，这是一个大规模的
parallel eyes system so because it's
平行眼睛系统因为它是
sequential the clock speed matters
顺序时钟速度很重要
because that's how fast essentially
因为那基本上有多快
those instructions are able to be
这些说明是 可以的
executed and so we're we're leveling off
执行，所以我们正在平稳
physics is stopping us from continuing
物理学阻止我们继续前进
Moore's Law so Intel AMD are
摩尔定律使 英特尔AMD都
aggressively pushing this Moore's law
积极推动摩尔定律
forward but and there's some promise
前进，但有一些承诺
that it will actually continue for
它实际上将继续
another ten or fifteen years then
再过十年或十五年
there's another form of parallelism
还有另一种形式的并行性
massive parallelism is the GPU and this
大规模并行是GPU和这个
is this is essential for neural networks
这对神经网络至关重要
this is essential to the success recent
这 对最近的成功至关重要
success of neural networks is the
神经网络的成功是
ability to utilize these inherently
能够有效地利用这些
parallel architectures of graphics
并行 的图形 架构
processing units GPUs the same thing
处理单元GPU同样的事情
used for video games this is the this is
用于视频游戏 这是 这个
the reason Nvidia stock
Nvidia股票的原因
doing extremely well is is GPUs so it's
做得非常好的是GPU，所以它是
parallelism of basic computational
基本计算的并行性
processes that make machine learning
使机器学习的过程
work on the GPU one of the limitations
在GPU上工作的一个局限
of GPUs one of the challenges is in
GPU 的挑战之一是
bringing them to in scaling and bringing
带他们去扩展和带来
them into real-world applications this
他们进入现实世界的 应用程序
power usage its power consumption and so
电力使用其 耗电量等
there is a lot of specialized chips
有很多专门的芯片
specialized just from the neural network
专门 从神经网络
architectures coming out from Google
来自Google的架构
with their tensor processing unit from
他们的张量处理单元来自
IBM Intel and so on it's unclear how far
IBM英特尔等等还不清楚到底有多远
this goes so this is sort of the
这就是这样 的
direction of trying to design an
尝试设计 的 方向
electronic brain so it has the
电子大脑所以它有
efficiency our human brain is
人类大脑的效率
exceptionally efficient at running the
在运行时非常有效率
neural networks in our heads and the
我们头脑中的神经网络
orders of magnitude more efficient than
比 数量级 更高效 的数量级
our computers are and this is trying to
我们的电脑正在努力
design systems they're able to grow
他们能够成长的设计系统
towards that efficiency why do you care
为了这个效率 你为什么关心
about efficiency for several reasons one
关于效率 有几个原因之一
of course as I'm sure will talk about
当然，我肯定 会 谈论
throughout this class is about the thing
整个课程都讲述了这 件事
in our smart phones battery usage and
在我们的 智能手机电池使用和
this is the big one community I think I
这是我 认为的大社区
think it could be attributed to the big
认为这可能是 由于 大
breakthroughs in machine learning
机器学习的突破
recently in the last decade is the you
最近十年是你
know compute as important algorithm
知道计算是重要的算法
development is important but it's the
发展是重要的，但它是
community of nerds global this is global
这 是全球性的书呆子社区
artificial intelligence and I will show
我将展示人工智能
in several ways why global is essential
在几个方面， 全球化至关重要
here is is tens of hundreds of thousands
这里是几十万
millions of programmers Mechanical
数百万程序员 机械
Engineers building robots building
建造机器人的工程师
intelligent systems building machine
智能系统建筑机器
learning algorithms the exciting nature
学习算法令人兴奋的本质
of the growth of the community perhaps
也许社区的成长
is the key for the future to unlock in
是 未来 解锁 的关键
the power of machine learning so this is
这是机器学习的力量
just one example github is a repository
只有一个例子github是一个存储库
for code and this is showing on the
代码，这 显示在
y-axis at the bottom is 2008 one github
底部的 y轴 是2008年的 一个github
first open
首先打开
Institute going up to 2012 quick near
研究所 快到 2012年 快速 接近
exponential growth of the number of
指数增长 的 数量
users participating and the number of
用户参与和数量
repositories so these are standalone
存储库所以这些是独立的
unique projects that are being hosted on
正在托管的独特项目
github so this is one example I'll show
github 所以这是 我要 展示的 一个例子
you about this competition that we're
关于这场 比赛， 我们是你
recently running and then I'll challenge
最近运行然后我会挑战
people here to participate in this
这里的人参与到 这个
competition if you dare so this is a
竞争，如果你敢， 所以这是一个
chance for you to build a neural network
你有机会建立一个神经网络
in your browser so you can do this on
在浏览器中 ，您可以执行此操作
your phone
您的手机
later tonight of course on your phone
今晚晚些时候当然在你的手机上
you can specify various parameters of
你可以指定各种参数
the neural network specify different
神经 网络指定 不同
numbers of layers and the depth the
层数 和深度
depth of the network the number of
网络深度的数量
neurons in network the type of layers
网络中 的 神经元 是层的类型
and it's pretty it's pretty
它非常漂亮
self-explanatory it's super easy in
不言自明，这是非常容易的
terms of just tweaking little things and
只是调整一些小东西的条款
remember machine learning to a large
记得机器学习到一个大的
part is an art at this point it's a more
部分是一种艺术，在这一点上它是一个 更多
perhaps than even you know more than a
也许甚至比你知道的多了一个
well understood theoretically bounded
很好 理解在理论上有限
science which is one of the challenges
科学这是挑战之一
but it's also an opportunity deep
但这也是一个 深刻 的机会
traffic is a chance so we've all been
交通是一个机会， 所以我们都是
stuck in traffic
堵在路上
there you go Americans spend 8 billion
你去美国人花费80亿美元
hours stuck in traffic every year
每年都有几个小时的交通堵塞
that's our pitch for this competition so
这是我们参加本次比赛的投手
deep neural networks can help and so you
深度神经网络可以 帮助你
have a neural network that drives that
有一个驱动它的神经网络
little car with an MIT logo red one on
车很少有MIT的标志 红色 的
this highway and tries to weave in and
这条高速公路， 并试图编织和
out of traffic to get to his destination
没有交通到达目的地
and trying to achieve a speed of 80
并试图 达到80的速度
miles an hour which is the speed limit
每小时一英里，这 是 速度限制
which is a physical speed limit of the
这是一个物理速度限制
car of course the actual speed limit of
汽车当然是实际的 速度限制
the road is 65 miles an hour but we
这条路是每小时 65英里， 但 我们
don't care about that we just want to
不关心 ，我们只是想
get to work as quickly as possible at
去尽可能 快地在 工作
home so what the basic structure of this
回家，所以什么这个基本结构
game is and I want to explain this game
游戏是，我想解释这个游戏
a little bit and then tell you how
一点点 ，然后告诉你如何
incredibly popular it's gotten and how
非常受欢迎它已经得到了如何
incredibly powerful the networks that
令人难以置信的强大的网络 ，
people built from all over the world the
人们建立 在世界各地 的
community has built of this over a
社区已经建立了这个
single month is incredible and this
单月是不可思议的，这个
happens for thousands of projects out
适用于数以千计的项目
there now another challenging
现在还有另一个挑战
opportunity ok so you may have seen this
机会好，所以你可能已经 看到了这一点
this is kind of ethics
这是一种道德规范
most engineers most I don't like I love
大多数工程师我最不喜欢我爱
the love philosophy but this kind of
爱情 哲学， 但这种
construction of ethics that's often
经常建构道德规范
presented here is one that is not
这里介绍的是一个 不是
usually concerned to engineering so what
通常关注工程 所以是什么
is this question you know when you have
你有这个问题吗？
a car you have a bunch of pedestrians do
车你有一堆行人 做 的
you hit the larger group of pedestrians
你击中了更大的一群行人
or the smaller group of pedestrians do
或者较小的一群行人
you avoid the group of pedestrians but
你避开了一群行人但是
put yourself into danger these kinds of
把自己变成危险 这类
ethical questions of an intelligent
智慧的 道德问题
system it's a very interesting question
系统 这是一个非常有趣的问题
it's it's one that we can debate and
这 是我们可以 辩论 的一个
there's really no good answer quite
真的没有好的答案
honestly but it's a problem that both
说实话，但它是一个问题的 两个
humans and machines struggle with and so
人类和机器都在与之斗争
it's not interesting on the engineering
它对工程学没有意义
side we're interested with problems that
方面 ，我们有兴趣与问题，
we can solve on the engineering side so
我们 可以在工程 方面 解决 这样
the kind of problem that I am obsessed
我痴迷的那种问题
with and very interested in is the
和非常感兴趣的是
real-world problem of controlling a
现实世界 的控制问题
vehicle through this space so there's it
通过这个空间的车辆就 这样了
happens in in a few seconds here so this
发生在几秒钟，所以 这
is a Manhattan New York intersection
是纽约曼哈顿的一个十字路口
right
对
this is pedestrians walking perfectly
这是行人走路完美
legally I think they have a green light
从法律上讲，我认为他们有绿灯
of course there's a lot of jaywalking
当然有很多 jaywalking
too as well well this car just slide
这辆车也滑得很好
it's not part of the point but yes
这不是重点，但是是的
exactly there's an ambulance and so
确切地说有一辆救护车等等
there's another car that starts making a
有启动制作另一辆车
left turn in a little bit I may have
我可能有一点左转
missed it hopefully not so yeah and then
错过了希望不是 这样， 然后
there's another car after that too that
还有 之后的另一辆车 太 那个
just illustrates when you design an
只是说明 你设计的时候
algorithm that's supposed to move
应该移动的算法
through the space like watch this car
透过空间就像看这辆车一样
the aggression it shows now this isn't a
它现在表现出的侵略性 不是 一个
trivial example for those that try to
那些尝试的人的简单例子
build robots this is this is the real
建造机器人这是真实的
question is how do you design a system
问题是你如何设计 一个系统
that's able so you have to think you
这样你就得想到你了
have to put reward functions objective
必须把奖励功能作为目标
functions utility functions under which
函数实用函数
it performs the planning so a car like
它执行规划，所以像汽车一样
that has several thousand candidate
有几千个候选人
trajectories you can take that
轨迹可以采取
intersection you can take a trajectory
交叉路口你可以走一条轨道
where it speeds up to 60 miles an hour
它的速度可达每小时60英里
it doesn't stop and just swerves and
它不 停止，只是转向和
hits everything okay that's a bad
点击一切 都没关系
trajectory right then there is a
轨迹正确然后有一个
trajectory which most companies take
大多数公司采取的轨迹
which is most a Google self-driving car
这是大多数 谷歌自动驾驶汽车
and every company that's is concerned
和每家公司 这 是关注
about PR is whenever there's any kind of
关于PR，无论什么时候都有
obstacle any
障碍任何
kind of risk that's it all reasonable
这种风险是完全合理的
that you can maybe even touch an
你甚至可以碰一下
obstacle then you're not going to take
然后你不会采取障碍
that trajectory so what that means is
这个轨迹所以 这意味着 什么
you're going to navigate to this
你要 导航到此
intersection at 10 miles an hour and you
和你一起以每小时10英里的路口行驶
let people abuse you by walking in front
让人们走在前面虐待你
of you because they know you're not
你 是因为他们知道你不是
going to stop and so in the middle there
要停下来，所以在 中间那里
is hundreds thousands of trajectories
是成千上万的轨迹
that are ethically questionable in the
这在道德上是有问题 的
sense that you're putting other human
感觉到你正在把其他人
beings at risk in order to safely and
生命危险，以安全和
successfully navigate to an intersection
成功导航到十字路口
and the design of those objective
以及 那些目标 的设计
functions is is the kind of question you
功能是是那种 问题 的 你
have to ask for intelligent systems fork
不得不要求 智能系统 叉
for cars is there's no grandma and a few
对于汽车而言，没有奶奶和少数
children you have to choose who gets to
孩子你必须选择 谁 去
die very very difficult problems of
死得非常困难的问题
course but the problem of when I'm very
当然但问题是 我什么时候
interested in in streets of Boston
对波士顿的街道感兴趣
streets of New York is how to gently
纽约的街道是如何轻轻地
nudge yourself through a crowd of
通过一群人轻推自己
pedestrians in the way we all actually
我们所有人实际上都是行人
do when we drive in New York in order to
当我们在纽约指令行驶办
be able to safely navigate these
能够安全地 导航这些
environments and these questions come up
环境和这些问题 出现了
in healthcare these questions come up in
在医疗保健中， 这些问题出现了
Factory in robust in in armed and
工厂在武装和武装的强大
humanoid robots that operate with other
与其他人一起操作的类人机器人
human beings and that's one of the big
人类，这是一个 大的
challenges another sort of funny
挑战另一种有趣的
illustration that folks that openly I
插图是乡亲 公开我
use often to illustrate well let me just
经常用来 说明我的意思
pause for a second the the gamified
停顿一秒钟游戏化
version of this there's a game called
这个版本有一个叫做的游戏
coast runners and you're you're racing
海岸跑步者 ，你在赛跑
against other boats along this track and
对抗沿着这条赛道的其他船只
your job is
你的工作是
there's your score here at the
这里有你的分数
bottom-left number of laps your time and
左下角 的圈数 你的时间和
you're trying to get to the destination
你想到达目的地
as quickly as possible while also
尽可能快地 同时
collecting funky little things like
收集时髦的小东西
there's these green these green little
这些绿色的绿色很少
things along the way okay so what
一路上的事情 还可以
they've done is the bill Denton system
他们所做的是丹顿系统的法案
the one the general-purpose one that we
我们这个通用的那个
talked about last time that learns oops
谈到上次 学习oops的时候
that learns how to navigate successfully
学习如何 成功导航
through the space so you're trying to
穿过空间， 所以你想要
maximize the reward and what this boat
最大化奖励和这艘船
learns to do is instead of finishing the
学会做的不是完成
race it learns to find a loop
比赛它学会找到一个循环
it can keep going around and around
它可以继续 下去 了一圈又一圈
collecting those green dots and it
收集 那些绿点和它
learns the fact that they regenerate
了解他们重生 的事实
with time so learns to maximize this
随着时间的推移，学会最大化这个
score by going around and round now
现在四处走动得分
these are the kinds of things this is
这些都是各种各样的事情 ，这 是
the big challenge of our award functions
我们的 奖项功能 面临 巨大 挑战
of designing systems of designing what
设计系统的设计
you want your system to achieve is not
你希望你的系统实现 不是
only is it difficult to the ethical
只有 道德 很难
questions are difficult but just
问题很困难， 但只是
avoiding the pitfalls of local optima of
避免当地最优的陷阱
vet figuring out something really good
兽医找出一些 非常好的 东西
that happens in the short-term the
这种情况发生在 短期内
greedy what it is that those psychology
贪心那些心理学 是什么
experiments of the kid eats the
孩子的实验吃了
marshmallow and can't wait for you know
棉花糖，不能等你知道
can't delayed gratification this kind of
不能延迟满足 这种
the idea of delayed gratification in the
在延迟满足的想法
case of designing intelligent system was
设计智能系统的案例是
a huge actual serious problem and this
一个巨大的实际严重问题和这个
is a good illustration of that so we
这是一个很好的例证，所以我们
flew through a few concepts here is
这里介绍了一些概念
there any is there any questions about
有没有任何问题
some of the compute and the algorithm
一些计算和 算法
side we talked about today yes
我们今天谈到的一面是的
so the question was yeah used you
所以问题是你用过的
highlighted some of the limitations of
强调了一些局限性
machine computer vision algorithms
机器计算机视觉算法
machine learning algorithms but you
机器学习算法，但你
haven't highlighted some of the
没有突出一些
limitations of human beings and if you
人类的局限， 如果你
put those in a column and you compare
把它们放在一个列中 然后进行比较
those it's our machines doing better
那些是我们的机器做得更好
overall or is there any kind of way to
整体还是有任何 方式
compare those I mean that there's
比较那些我的意思是 有的
actually interesting work on image net
实际上有关图像网的有趣工作
so image net is this categorization task
所以image net就是这个分类任务
of where you have to classify images and
你必须在哪里分类图像 和
you can ask the question when I present
我出席时你可以问这个问题
you images of cats and dogs where our
你的猫狗图像在哪里
machine is better than humans and when
机器比人类 更好
when are they not so you can compare
什么时候不是这样你可以比较
when machines do better what are the
当机器做得更好的时候
fail points and what are the fail points
失败点和失败点是什么
for humans and there's a lot of
对于人类和有很多的
interesting visual perception questions
有趣的视觉感知问题
there I think overall it's certainly
在那里， 我认为总的来说肯定
true that machines fail differently than
确实，机器的失败方式不同于
human beings but in order to make an
人类， 但为了 做一个
artificial intelligence system that's
这是人工智能系统
usable and could make you a lot of money
可用，可以让你 赚 很多 钱
and people would want to use it has to
并且人们会想要使用它
be better for that particular task in
对于 那个 特定的任务 更好
every single way in order in order for
按顺序排列的每一种方式
you to want to use a system
你想要使用 一个系统
has to be it has to be superior to human
必须是它 优于人类
performance and usually far superior to
性能通常远优于
human performance so so it's on the
人类的 表现 所以它就是这样的
philosophical level it's an interesting
哲学层面 这是一个有趣的
thing to compare what are we good at
比较我们擅长什么的 东西
what are not but if you're using Amazon
什么不是， 但如果你使用亚马逊
echo your voice recognition or any kind
回应您的语音识别或任何形式
of natural language chatbots or a car
自然语言 聊天机器人 或汽车
you're not gonna be well this car is not
你不会 好， 这辆车不行
so good with pedestrians but I
行人这么好，但我
appreciate the fact that you can stay in
欣赏你可以留下来的事实
the lane fortunately you have a very
幸运的是你有一个非常好的车道
high standard for every single thing
每件事都很高标准
that you're good at and it has to be
你很擅长 ，它必须 是
superior to that I I think maybe maybe
优于 II想，也许，也许
that's unfair to the robots I'm more of
这对我更喜欢的机器人是不公平的
the nerd that makes the technology
制造技术的书呆子
happen but it's certainly on the
发生了， 但肯定是在
self-driving car aspect policy is
自动驾驶汽车方面的政策是
probably the biggest challenge and I
可能是我面临的最大挑战
don't think there's good answers there
不要认为 那里有好的答案
some of those ethical questions that
其中的一些伦理问题， 这
come up well it's it's it feels like so
好吧，这就是它的感觉
we work a lot with Tesla in Drive so I'm
我们在特斯拉 的 驱动器中工作很多， 所以我
driving a Tesla round every day and
驾驶着特斯拉一轮每天
we're playing around with it and
我们正在玩弄 它，
studying human behavior inside Tesla's
研究特斯拉的人类行为
and it seems like there's so much hunger
似乎有这么多的饥饿感
amongst the media to jump on something
在媒体中跳跃的东西
and it feels like a very shaky PR
这感觉就像一个非常 不稳定的公关
terrain a very shaky policy terrain
地形非常不稳定的政策地形
we're all walking because we have no
我们都走路了，因为我们没有
idea how how we coexist with intelligent
想法我们如何与智能共存
systems and so and and then of course
系统等等当然然后
government is nervous because how to
政府很紧张，因为如何
regulate the shaky terrain and
调节不稳定的地形和
everybody's nervous and excited so I'm
每个人都 紧张和兴奋，所以我
not sure there's no same kind of
不确定没有同样的
question to Jason a moment thanks a lot
向杰森提问的时刻非常感谢
legs for another great session
另一个伟大的会议的腿
[Applause]
[掌声]